怎么样？
Well？
- 我正在把程序传给你 - 嗯 我看到了 谢谢
- I'm sending you the code。- Yes，I see that。Thank you.
《虎胆龙威4》
- 那我的账户呢？- 正在转账
- What about my account？- Delivering.
刚传输完 你应该已经收到了
I just sent it。You should have it.
- 收到了 谢谢 - 嘿，你确定这是合法的吗？
- Yes。Thank you。- Hey，are you sure this is legal？
我们只是在给安全系统做测试 不会有问题的
We're just running a test on our security system，sir。It's fine.
你的声音可真性感 我还可以为你做些什么？
You've got a sexy voice。Is there anything else I can do for you？
- 或者对你做些什么？- 我们想要的已经都有了
- To you？- We have all we need.
准备好了
We're ready.
呦 猜猜谁刚到手了五万块钱？
Yo，guess who just made 50 Gs today.
- 你对我电脑做了什么？- 闭嘴 哥们儿 我可没动过它
- What'd you do to my drive？- I didn't touch it.
这样可不行 永远也不要动我的电脑
This isn't cool。Don't ever，ever touch my computer.
（华盛顿 美国联邦调查局网络安全部门）
分析报告没有显示出有任何损坏 但我们认为这次入侵是有人故意为之
Diagnostics show no damage，but this was an intentional breach.
- 你是说我们被黑了？- 不过还没达到拒绝服务的地步
- We were hacked？- It wasn't 「Denial of Service」 level，
但肯定是破了我们第一道防线
but they definitely cracked our door.
好吧！把黑名单拿出来
OK。Open the Black Hat files.
把全国所有可能做这事儿的黑客 都给我抓来问话 现在就办！
I want every hacker in the country who could have done this interviewed now.
长官 那可是有近一千人 现在又是假期的周末 我们已经人手不足了
Sir，that's close to 1，000 names。This holiday weekend we're short-staffed as it is.
听着 防止这类事件是我们的责任 可现在事情居然发生在我们身上 马上去做吧
We're the ones supposed to keep this from happening，and it happened to us。Do it.
长官 现在已经是晚上了 而且他们散布在全国各地
Sir，it's night。They're all over the country.
好吧 找当地执法部门帮忙
Get local law enforcement help.
既然有人觉得可以耍我们 我就要找出是谁
Somebody out there thinks they can screw with us。I wanna find out who.
- 吉姆！我说过不行！- 露西，你这是在折磨我 知道吗？
- Jim！I said no。- Lucy，you're killin' me，all right？
- 滚出来！- 干什么？！
- Get out！- What？！
- 马上滚出来！- 别碰我！
- Get out of the car now！- Don't touch me.
- 没人可以碰我的女儿 - 你要干什么？
- No means no。- What are you doin'？
- 约翰，住手！- 怎么啦？哦 别这么叫我 我讨厌你这样叫我
- John，stop it！- Don't call me that。I hate it when you do.
- 不 等一下 你认识这家伙？- 你给我闭嘴！
- You know this guy？- Just shut your mouth right now.
爸！住手 我不开玩笑
Dad！Stop it。I mean it.
- “爸”？你不是说你爸已经死了么 - 什么？
- 「Dad」？You said your dad was dead。- What？
你跟这混蛋说我死了？你真这么说的？
You told this jerk-off I was dead？You actually said that？
我可能是夸张了一点
I may have exaggerated a little bit.
那这家伙是谁？你男朋友？
And this guy's what？Your boyfriend？
- 不是！- 是！
- No。- Yeah.
我不知道 好了吗？对不起 只是…我们处处再说
I don't know，OK？I'm sorry。We'll see.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here？
- 你不接我电话 又不给我回电 - 那是因为我不会跟你说话的
- You don't answer your phone，return calls。- Because I'm not talking to you.
- 那这次又是因为什么呢 露西？- 因为什么？要我列给你听吗？
- Why aren't we talking this time，Lucy？- Why not？What？You want a list？
这个理由怎么样：你在监视我 跟踪我 还把我男朋友拉下车…
How about stuff like this：You spy on me，you drag my boyfriend out of the car…
- 你刚说他不是你男朋友 - 他的确不是！
- You said he's not your boyfriend。- He's not！
- 可你刚刚说我是 - 闭嘴
- I thought you said I just was。- Shut up.
你可真是个混蛋
You are such an asshole.
好吧 对不起 我把你的“非”男友拉下了车 行了吧？
OK。I'm sorry I pulled your 「not-boyfriend」 out of the car，OK？
- 好了 露西 宝贝儿 上车吧 咱们走 - 不 不行
- Lucy，baby，get in the car。Let's go。- No，no.
- 你们两个都给我走 行吗？- 就跟我谈一会儿 露西 就…
- Will both of you go away？- Just talk to me.
我累了 我要去睡觉…一个人睡！
I'm tired。I'm going to bed… alone.
见鬼了！你会一个人去睡觉
Damn right you're going to bed alone.
露西 孩子 等一下 我想跟你谈谈 就一会儿
Lucy，honey，wait a minute。I wanna talk to you。Just wait.
爸 等我想跟你谈的时候
Dad，when I wanna talk to you…
假如我想跟你谈的话
if I wanna talk to you…
我会给你打电话的
I'll call you.
露西 等一下 露西！露西…
Lucy。Wait，Lucy。Lucy！
- 露西·麦克连 - 我不姓麦克连 我姓杰尼洛
- Lucy McClane。- It's not McClane。It's Gennero.
哈哈 女人哪…
Chicks，right？
我走 我走
I'm gonna go。I'm gonna go.
约翰？
John？
约翰？是我 拉维诺
John？It's Sclavino.
- 麦克连回话 - 你在罗德纳做什么？
- Go for McClane。- What are you doing at Rutgers？
- 你怎么知道我在哪儿？- 我们的车在四年前就都装了追踪器 还记得吗？
- How do you know where I am？- Our cars were LoJacked four years ago.
- 我现在就正看着你的具体所在地呢 - 长官 这项功能我可好像没有启动哪
- I'm staring at exactly where you are。- Sir，that's not something I would turn on.
对 是我们启动的
Yeah，we did that。John，we turned them on.
约翰 我们只能这么做 听着 联邦调查局的人打电话来要我们协助
Listen，the feds have called in a favour.
他们在做一项排查工作 想要我们去接一个 住在卡姆登的电脑黑客
They're doing a sweep。They want us to pick up some computer hacker in Camden.
他姓法瑞尔 名字叫马修
Last name：Farrell。First name：Matthew.
好么 卡姆登？你跟我说这些干什么？
Whoa，whoa。Camden？What are you telling me this for？
- 刚到的 - 伙计 现在是凌晨三点 我已经在回家的路上了
- Just came in。- Vino，it's 3am。I was on my way home.
随便在警校找个便衣得了 他乐不得的呢
Send ajughead from the Academy。They'd be happy to do it.
我不能随便找个便衣！局里要求一定得是个高级探员
I can'tjust send in a uniform。The feds demanded a senior detective.
这孩子好像是个重要人物 我也不清楚
The kid's a high-value subject，I don't know.
你去接他就是了 护送他到华盛顿的 联邦办公楼
Just pick him up，escort him to the Hoover Building in DC.
他们那儿今天早上发生了一起 电脑入侵事件
They had some kind of a computer breach there this morning.
“太好了”！
Great！
好吧 把刚才那些资料告诉我 再说一遍他名字 是什么？
All right，give me that information。Give me that name again。What is it？
你可欠我一人情啊 杰克.
You owe me one，Jack.
（已连接 法瑞尔·马修）
（你认为有多糟糕？）
（非常糟糕）
（能指望你吗？）
（不行）
（建议呢？）
（马上消失）
（离线）
怎么？
What？
（上传病毒… 完毕）
哦 别介呀
Aw，come on.
他妈的
Goddammit.
开始执行B计划
- 谁？- 纽约警局的 请开下门
- Who is it？- NYPD。Open the door，please.
- 你好 - 你是纽约警局的？
- Hi。- NYPD？
哦 我明白了 不用担心 之前也有人 在这块儿迷路的 我很乐意帮忙 你走…
OK。Oh，I get it。Don't worry，everyone gets lost around here。Glad to help。Take…
嘿 我没有迷路 你是马特…马修·法瑞尔吗？
Hey，I'm not lost。Are you Matthew Farrell？
不是 他 嗯…现在已经不住这儿了
No。He，uh… actually does not live here any more.
- 当然了 那你是谁？- 我叫戴茜·杜克
- Course not。Who are you？- My name is Daisy Duke.
我小时候已经被取笑过无数次了 拜托别再取笑我了
Got a lot of shit for it when I was a kid。Please don't add to it.
- 可以看一下你的证件吗？- 行 当然可以
- Can I see some identification，please？- Yeah，sure.
哦！“探员”！
Oh，「Detective」！
看起来跟真的一样！从玩具城弄来的？还挺不错的嘛
Yeah，that looks real！You get that at Toys 「R」 Us？Looks great.
- 当然还有… - 对 那个…看起来确实不错
- Then of course… - Yeah。That… actually looks pretty good.
嗯
Mmm.
法瑞尔！有人刚破解了杀戮地带9的最新版 想过来看一眼吗？
Farrell！Sully PDL-ed the new copy of the Kill Zone Nine。Wanna check it out？
不了！谢谢 你可真会挑时候
No！Thanks，though，man。And good luck at the Bad Timing Awards.
开门吧
Open the door.
靠！
Shit.
想喝点儿什么？咖啡？啤酒？
Can I get you something？Coffee？A warrant？
- 到底是因为什么事？- 我不清楚 跟电脑有关
- What's this about？- I don't know。Some computer thing.
联邦调查局的人想找你谈话 咱们走吧
DC feds wanna talk to you，so let's go.
- 联邦调查局的人？- 对 联邦调查局的人
- Feds，huh？- Yeah。The feds.
我有四年时间都是在白名单上的 没犯什么事 可是自从上了他妈的那个黑名单之后…
I've been White Hat for four years，but once you're on that goddamn list…
真他妈混蛋
Such a pain in the ass.
- 你玩儿玩具模型？- 嗯？
- You play with dolls？- Huh？
- 你能不能别动那个 - 是类似于特种部队之类的玩具？
- Could you not touch that？- Like a GI Joe？
不 不是 那个是限量版的…
No，it's not。It's a limited edition…
- 哦 - 呃…
- Ooh。- …and…
- 这个是应该能拆下来的吗？- 不应该 不过它坏了以后会更值钱
- That supposed to come off？- No，but it's more valuable broken，
- 所以我得谢谢你 - 可以用胶粘一下 它肯定是挺重要的
- so thanks for that。- Krazy Glue。I'm sure it's very important.
我还有其他一些不错的模型 要不要再弄坏几个？
I got some other cool shit you can break.
- 咱们走吧，好吗？来吧 - 我得关机呀 明白？
- Let's go，OK？Come on。- I gotta power down my gear，OK？
都是些模型 看来你不常 和女孩子约会
More dolls。Not spending a whole lot of time with the girls，huh？
嘿！你还真想逃跑啊？
Hey！Are you really trying to escape？
哦！天，别开枪！
Ow！Jesus，don't shoot！
趴下！
Get down！
- 我老天 - 待着别动
- Jesus Christ。- Stay right there.
走！
Go！
咱们走 快点儿！低点儿 低点儿！趴下！
Let's go。Come on。Low，low！Stay down！
- 啊！- 快！
- Agh！- Come on.
没事儿的 趴低点儿 懂吗？别起来
It's all right。Stay low，all right？Stay down.
- 别离开我！好 我们走！- 好
- You stay with me，all right？Here we go。- OK.
好的
OK.
看来邻居们要被吵醒了
That'll wake the neighbours.
趴下！到里面去！
Get down！Get inside！
他们又回屋里去了！
They're back in the room！They're back in the room！
你疯了吗？快离开那儿！
Are you nuts？Get outta there right now！
- 我只是想… - 快！
- I'm trying to… - Now！
快回那后面去！
Get back in there！
啊！
Aaargh！Argh！
准备逃跑！
Get ready to run.
- 那到底是怎么回事？- 什么呀？
- What the hell was that？- What？
- 是你干的吗？- 不是
- Did you do that？- No.
- 操 - 不是我干的 走吧
- Shit。- I didn't do that。Come on.
- 妈的！- 跟紧点儿
- Shit。- Stay close。The whole apartment's on fire.
来 咱们走吧 快 走吧 他妈的！
Come on。Let's go。Come on，let's go，goddammit！
来
Come on.
小心 你能不能慢点儿
Watch it。Slow it down.
哦 上帝
Oh，my God。Oh，my God.
嘿 咱们走 快！
Hey，let's go。Come on.
快！跟上！
Come on，come on。Stay close.
跟着我 跟着我
Stay with me。Stay with me.
来 咱们走！跟紧了我！
Come on，let's go。Stay close.
上车！快 快！
Get in the car。Go，go.
- 小子 你会上子弹吗？- 什么？我吗？
- Kid，can you reload a gun？- What？Me？
- 会上子弹吗？！- 我…
- Can you reload a gun？！- I…
快把储备箱打开 找备用子弹给枪换上！
Open the glove box and get a magazine out right now！
快去拿车后座上的枪！
Grab the gun from the back seat！
你没事儿吧？
You OK？
把头低下！
Get your head down.
老天！这身手 难道是马戏团进城了？
Jesus！Is the circus in town？
- 你看到了吗？- 当然 那是我干的
- Did you see that？- Yeah，I saw it。I did it.
呼叫卡姆登总部10077 请回应！卡姆登总部10077！
Camden base，10077。Come back。Camden base，10077.
卡姆登总部回话 请说
Go ahead.
我要跟你们的探长说话 紧急事件 请速转达
I need to speak to your chief of your detectives。Police emergency，asap.
请稍等
Stand by.
- 我是维斯纳探长 - 我是约翰·麦克连 纽约警局探员
- This is Chief Detective Wiesman。- This is Detective John McClane，NYPD.
报告紧急情况 在你辖区内发生一起袭警事件
Police emergency。I wanna report a police shooting in yourjurisdiction.
你跟他说
- 喂？- 情况怎么样了？
- Yeah？- What's the status？
还没搞定他
我们损失了三个人
等一下
Wait one.
汤玛斯 新泽西那边出了问题 法瑞尔还活着
Thomas。We had a problem in New Jersey。Farrell's still alive.
- 让他跑了？- 是的
- So he got away。- Yeah.
我可是派了你们五个人过去的 对吧？
I did send five of you，is that right？
是的 但是又突然出现了另外一个人
我派直升机去接你们 从空中去找他们 的行踪 这你能办得到吧？
I'm sending a chopper。Get airborne and we'll track 'em down。Think you can handle that？
- 哦 上帝！- 深呼吸就好了
- Oh，my God。- Just breathe.
我已经在深呼吸了！我 我…就是没法停止发抖
I am breathing！I'm-I'm… I can't stop shaking.
是激素的作用 你只不过是被吓到了 会过去的！
It's the adrenaline。You're just scared。It'll pass.
对 我被吓到了！难道你刚才就不害怕吗？
Yeah，I'm scared！Weren't you scared，back there？
是的 我也害怕
Yeah。I was scared.
是吗？这就是你害怕的样子？我可说不清 但你看起来非常的冷静
Really？This is you being scared？I don't know，cos you seem really calm.
你以前也做过那样的事么？
Have you done stuff like that before？
- 什么样的事？- 杀人之类的
- Stuff like what？- Like killing people.
做过 不过已经是很久以前了
Yeah。But not for a long time.
那刚刚那些是什么人？他们为什么要杀你？
So who were those guys，huh？Why were they trying to kill you？
为什么还他妈把我的公寓给炸了？！
Why did they blow up my goddamn apartment？！
他们是去杀你的
They were there to kill you.
- 他们为什么要杀我？- 该你来告诉我 小子！你才是犯人
- Why would they want to kill me？- You tell me，kid。You're the criminal.
到目前为止已经有七个黑客死了 都不是在黑名单上名列前茅的
We got seven dead hackers so far，none of whom were high on our list.
- 回收他们的硬盘做调查 - 是 长官！
- Get the hard drives，start sweepin' 'em。- Yes，sir.
特雷 马修·法瑞尔 给我找到他
Trey。Matthew Farrell，find him for me.
马上办！
On it.
那么多枪是做什么用的？
What's with all the guns？
为了谨慎起见
Operational prudence.
就当它们是硬件 跟你们这些软件配套的
Think of them as hardware to your software.
早安 华盛顿！看起来今天又会是独立日假期里一个美丽的周末
Good morning，DC！It's shaping up to be a beautiful Fourth of July weekend.
如果你有什么盛大的计划 最好早点出发了 因为交通似乎已经开始拥堵了
If you've got any big plans，get started early，cos the traffic is ramping up.
好！这里就再为正在出行的人们 送出一首经典老歌
So here's another golden oldie for all the commuters out there.
怎么？怎么…怎么回事…
What？What… What…
你在干嘛？这是什么呀？
What are you doing？What is that？
- 这是Creedence的歌 - Creedence？
- It's Creedence。- Creedence？
是Creedence。Creedence Clearwater Revival乐队 经典摇滚乐
Creedence。Creedence Clearwater Revival？Classic rock？
我知道是谁 是很老没错 但这并不代表就是经典
I know who it is。It's old rock。Doesn't make it classic.
- 以前很烂 到现在还是很烂 - 你不喜欢Creedence？
- What sucked then sucks now。- You don't like Creedence？
感觉就像是把松果塞到我屁股里一样
This is like having a pine cone shoved in my ass.
好啊 你就这样？可真是成熟啊
OK。Really？Wow，that's mature.
拜托 伙计 我已经跟你很合作了
Come on。I'm cooperating with you.
航行角度060 第二次搜查
We're at a heading of 060。Making another pass.
大家听着 都准备好了吗？
Listen up，everyone。Are we ready？
交通网的交换机已准备好了
Transportation hubs are prepped and set.
第一阶段行动开始
Begin stage one.
（华盛顿 交通控制中心）
怎么了？没什么
What？Nothing.
你上一次打开收音机听流行音乐是什么时候？告诉我一个大概的年代就可以了
When'd you last turn on the radio and listen to popular music？Just give me a decade.
70年代？我只是在猜… 那时候麦克尔·杰克逊还是黑人吧？
The '70s？I'm guessing。Was Michael Jackson still black？
我们倒退10年 Pearl Jam听过么？那就20年 The Cure乐队 也没听说过？
Pearl Jam。I'll go back ten years with you。Ten years.20 years。The Cure？Nothin'？
这个可是新闻广播 我想听听昨晚你在 卡姆登的那些“朋友”有没有上头条
It's called news radio。I want to see if your friends from Camden made the headlines.
等一下… 你还听新闻哪？
Hold on。You listen to the news？
是啊 你现在又对新闻有意见了？
You got a problem with the news now？
意见大了去了
Yeah。I got a big goddamn problem with the news.
听好了 所谓的新闻 都是被人为操纵的
Ready for this？The news is completely manipulated.
你每天所听到的每句话
Everything you hear，every single day，
都是媒体为了一个目的而设计的 那就是让你活在恐惧之中
is designed by corporate media to do one thing only：To keep you living in fear.
- 噢 恐惧？- 绝对的恐惧
- Oh，fear？- Total fear.
这样你就会出去花钱买东西 一些你根本用不上或已经有的东西
So you'll go out and spend money on things you probably don't even need，
这样广告商就会在电台上 不断地花钱打广告
so advertisers keep buying ads on their stations.
我还要告诉你一件事 你听好了 我可以说上一天的时间 家里还有 几天也看不完的数据可以证明…
I'll tell you one more thing。I'll do this all day。I got days of data at home…
- 嘿！- 我会全面颠覆你的…
- Hey。- I'll drop a bomb on you…
- 嘿！- 怎么了？
- Hey！- What？
- 闭嘴！- 好吧 好吧 宁愿选择逃避问题也不…
- Shut up。- That's good。Be dismissive instead of…
- 你没事吧？- 不 我有事！
- You all right？- No，I'm not all right！
待在车里就会没事的
Just stay in the car。You'll be all right.
喂！先生 喂！
Hey，man。Hey.
你没事吧？不要动 打911就行了 好吗？
You all right？Don't move。Just call 911，all right？
好的
OK.
老天
Jesus Christ.
- 所有的信号灯都变绿了 - 什么？
- All the lights are green。- Huh？
所有的信号灯都变绿了 咱们走吧 快
All the lights are green。Let's go。Right now.
- 我们得走了？- 拿着你的包 黑客小子 走吧！
- We gotta go？- Get your bag，hack-boy。Let's go.
- 咱们走 - 我还从来没经历过交通事故
- Let's go。- I've never been in a car accident.
嗯 的确很刺激 这边走 过来！
Well，it's very exciting。This way，come on.
- 你经历过交通事故吗？- 是的
- You been in a car accident？- Yeah.
我们这是要干什么？
What are we doing？
这是一项60年代的小发明 叫做跑步 你会喜欢的 来吧
It's a little thing they invented in the '60s called jogging。You're gonna love it.
长官 芝加哥报告说他们的高架铁路 控制网系统瘫痪
Sir，Chicago's reporting a systems crash on the el train network.
美铁那里的通讯系统正在发出一级警报
Amtrak is flashing a level-one crash in their com system.
联邦航空局刚发出了紧急报告 他们的自动定时系统崩溃了
FAAjust issued a critical alert。Their ATC netjust went down.
我们被攻击了
We're under attack.
好 现在咱们让他们都出去 呼吸呼吸新鲜空气
OK，let's get 'em outside for a little fresh air.
是炭疽病毒警报
That's the anthrax alarm.
好吧！大家都出去！就现在！快！
All right，everyone out。Now！Now！
泰勒 走！快走！
Taylor，move！Go！Move！
所有人员注意 请迅速撤出 并到停车场处集合
All personnel must evacuate and proceed to the transportation shuttles immediately.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
所有人员注意 请迅速撤出 并到停车场处集合
All personnel must evacuate and proceed to the transportation shuttles immediately.
长官 里面有事需要您处理
We need you inside，sir.
带上你的人 上到四楼去 明白吗？戴好防毒面具
Take your team。I want men on the fourth floor，got it？Masks on.
我们得弄清那儿到底有什么
We gotta know what's there.
给我查找所有的系统出错信息 看能不能找到源头
Run a trunk search on these data crashes，try to ID the point of origin.
第二阶段行动开始
Begin stage two.
嘿 这是怎么回事？
Hey，what's going on？
他们已经开始恐慌了
They're already starting to panic.
那是当然的
Of course they are.
他们以为有人在抢他们的钱
They think that someone's taking their money.
那些他们辛辛苦苦攒下的每一个铜板
All those nickels and dimes they saved had meaning.
就像列宁说的 他们是“有利用价值的白痴”
「Useful idiots」，as Lenin would say.
准备好视频录像
Prep the video package.
华盛顿的交通系统快瘫痪了 他们还刚刚侵入了金融系统 所有的一切
DC transportation system's crashing and they just hit the financial sector。All of it.
给我接交通和财政部门的秘书 还有联邦商业委员会的主席
Get me the secretary for trans and treasury on the line and the chairman of the SEC.
大家行动起来！肯定有人在哪里留下了蛛丝马迹 去把它找出来！
Let's go，people。Somewhere somebody left a digital fingerprint。Find it.
- 副局长伯曼在吗？- 现在不行 你得等一下
- Deputy Director Bowman in here？- Not now。It'll have to wait.
今天不行？这是马修·法瑞尔 我按照伯曼的要求把他带来了
Not today。This is Matthew Farrell。I brought him here on orders from Bowman.
如果你搞不清状况的话 那就给我去找个明白人过来
If you don't know what's goin' on，find somebody that does.
我就是伯曼
I'm Bowman.
视频录像准备完毕 可以上传了
Video package is ready for upload.
听着 约翰！我很感谢你带法瑞尔过来
John，I appreciate your bringing Farrell，
但现在情况变了 我们正深陷危机之中 忙于控制局势呢
but we are neck-deep in damage control right now.
抱歉 长官 你们这儿有没有什么吃的？像点心之类的
Excuse me。I'm sorry，sir。Do you have anything to eat，any snacks around？
我想要… 我现在真的有点儿低血糖了…
I'd love… I've got really low blood sugar…
- 长官！- 没有吗？
- Sir？- No？
尽管出现了交通系统崩溃和炭疽病毒恐慌 但灾难还远远没有结束
As if the transportation breakdown and anthrax scares weren't enough for one day，
今天下午的股票市场又发生了 疯狂的清仓事件
the stock market found itself in a selling frenzy.
联邦商业委员会认为引发这次恐慌 的原因可能是
The FTC believes this panic might have been triggered
股票交易所内的计算机系统发生了故障
by a computer malfunction in the stock exchange.
哦 天啊！简直糟透了！
Oh，man，that is all bad.
实际上并没有看上去的那么糟糕 对付这类事件 我们早有防备
It's not as bad as it looks。We run drills to prepare for things like this.
- 这些都是嫌疑人吗？- 过去是
- These your suspects？- Were.
所有的七个人在过去的24个小时之内都被杀了
All seven were killed in the last 24 hours.
认识他们吗？
Recognise any of these people？
不认识
No.
一个也不认识？
Not one？
长官 出现一个系统错误
Sir，we got a system error.
我的美国同胞们… 现在是时候…
My fellow Americans… …it is time to…
把…恐惧…带入… 你们心中了…
strike… fear… into… the hearts of… citizenry.
- 不要问… - 这是未经批准的播出
- Ask not… - That's an unauthorised broadcast.
…你的国家能做些什么… 来避免…这次…危机
…what your country can do… to avert… this… crisis.
答案就是…毫无办法
The answer is… …nothing whatsoever.
我们的军事…力量…在这次事件当中…
Our military… strength… is… in this case…
…是…无能为力的
…useless.
听好我要说的话
Read my lips.
那个…伟大…而充满自信的…繁荣崛起… 美国的…发展…与…进步…
The… great… confident… roar… of… American… progress… and… growth…
已经走到了…尽头
has come to… an end.
所有的那些…关键性…技术… 那些被…这个国家…极为看重的…
All the… vital… technology… that… this nation… holds dear…
…通讯…交通…互联网…连接设备…
all… communications… transportation… the internet… connectivity…
电力…能源…重要…设施…
electrical… power… critical… utilities…
他们的…命运…现在…就在…我们的…掌控之中
their… fate… now… rests… in… our… hands.
我们不会疲倦 不会彷徨
We will not tire，we will not falter，
也不会失败
and we will not fail.
我真不知道他们是怎么侵入的
I don't know how they're getting in.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
还有…独立日快乐… 致你们每一个人
And a… happy Independence Day… to everyone.
真够吓人的
That was creepy.
我试着多找了几段尼克松的
I tried to find more Nixon.
你认为他们会买账吗？
Think they bought it？
绝对会
Absolutely.
好吧 帮我连接电信 交通 任何一个…
OK，I want telecom，transportation…
- 上帝！这是场末世入侵行动 - 是什么？
- Jesus Christ，it's a fire sale。- What？
是场末世入侵行动
It's a fire sale.
嘿 我们现在还不能知道呢
Hey。We don't know that yet.
- 那只不过是个传说 不可能实现的 - 只是个传说？是吗？
- It's a myth，anyway。It can't be done。- It's a myth？Really？
别告诉我她在这里还管事啊 顶多是个花瓶罢了
Please tell me she's not in charge of anything.
什么是末世入侵？
What's a fire sale？
这是个三步的系统入侵方案 可以摧毁整个国家的基本构成
It's a three-step systematic attack on the entire national infrastructure.
第一步：让交通系统瘫痪， 第二步：攻占金融和通讯系统
Step one：Take out transportation。Step two：The financial base and telecoms.
第三步：破坏所有设施 比如燃油、水利、电力、核设施…
Step three：Get rid of all the utilities，gas，water，electric，nuclear…
任何电脑控制的东西 这在今天简直就意味着一切
Anything that's run by computers，which today is almost everything.
这就是为什么他们叫它末世入侵 因为一切都得被清除
That's why they call it a fire sale，everything must go.
喂！听着 听着… 你叫什么来着？法瑞尔？
Hey，listen… What's your name？Farrell？
你小声点好吗？这里不准任何人提什么末世入侵的事
Keep your voice down，OK？No one here's talking about a fire sale.
除非你告诉我说你也参与策划了这种事件
Not unless you're telling me you helped plan one.
不是 哥们儿 我只是说…
No，man。I'm just saying…
感谢你的关心…我们都知道了 也在调查处理之中 谢谢你
Appreciate your concern。We're on it。Thank you.
- 你的工作到现在为止做得一团糟 - 什么？你说什么？
- You've done a bang-up job so far。- What？What？
没什么 我是说我明白了
Nothing。I said I understand.
嘿 他们可不是派个女童子军去杀这小子的
Hey。They didn't send the girl scouts out to get this kid.
他们用的是职业杀手 全副武装 把整个公寓都炸了
They sent professional guys，full tactical gear。They blew the whole joint up.
那 我不认识这孩子 说老实话这也不关我屁事 当然我没恶意啊
Now，I don't know this kid，and frankly I don't give a shit，no offence.
但有人想要这孩子的命
but somebody wants this kid dead，
而且很显然这跟现在 这里所发生的事情有某种联系
and obviously it's got something to do with whatever's going on here.
好吧 国土安全部现在负责询问所有被带来的黑客
OK。Homeland's interrogating the hackers we're bringing in.
我找个人陪同你们过去 行吗？
I'll get you an escort over there。All right？
莫利纳 保证这孩子优先被询问 我想知道他到底知道什么
Molina，get this kid to the front of the line。I wanna know what he knows.
他要是知道我所了解事情的一半 他那小鸟头就该爆炸了
If he knew half the shit I know，his head would explode.
我是特别事务员詹森 我们做这辆车走
Special Agent Johnson。We'll take the sedan.
- 事务员詹森？- 没错 这边请
- Agent Johnson？- That's right。Right this way.
“太棒了”！你刚才说的事真的有可能发生吗？
Great。So is any of that actually possible，what you were saying back there？
可能吗？好 你看 如果只拿走其中一样东西 系统是可以自动恢复的
Is it possible？Look，you take out any one thing，the system can recover.
如果你一次就把所有的都弄垮 那系统就崩溃了…你看看你周围就知道了
If you take it all down at once，the system crashes and… Look around，man.
得了 政府有几十个部门专门处理这事儿呢
Come on。Government's gotta have dozens of departments dedicated to that shit.
别忘了上次闹飓风时紧急事务处理部门 可是花了五天时间才把水送到新奥尔良体育馆哪
It took FEMA five days to get water to the Superdome.
我们还要多久才能到国土安全部？
How long till we get to DHS？
罗夫林 帮我联系华盛顿警察分队 让他们给我们清出条路来去国土安全部
Laughlin，get on the DC police band and get 'em to clear a route to DHS for us.
华盛顿交警队 我们是联邦调查局 请求你们清出一条路…
DC Metro，this is the FBI requesting you to clear a route…
法瑞尔终于浮出水面了
Farrell just resurfaced on the grid.
- 联邦调查局的人正带他去国土安全部 - 很好
- Feds are taking him to Homeland。- Good.
- 马上截断他们的通话 - 隔离通话频率
- Close that loop，now。- Isolate the frequency.
找出汽车的具体位置 再给我把这个约翰·麦克连的档案调出来看看
Get us a location on the vehicles and pull me up a file on this John McClane.
兰德 我们刚找到法瑞尔 准备追踪他的具体位置
Rand，we just found Farrell。Stand by for a location.
听着 伙计们！我不想找麻烦 可咱们刚 经过了一个汉堡店 我已经快饿死了…
I don't mean to harp，but we just passed another Arby's，and I'm starving.
- 我连包装纸都可以吃了 - 闭嘴！
- I could eat a wrapper。- Shut up.
- 就算是只吃番茄酱包也行 - 闭嘴！
- I could just get some ketchup packets。- Shut up.
给你十四分钟时间来解释一下 之前为什么要骗我
You got about 14 minutes to tell me why you lied to me.
骗你？你…你在说什么？
Lied to you？What are you talking about？
墙上的那些照片 你认识那些人 对吧？
The pictures on the wall，you knew those guys.
- 我不… - 孩子 别骗我
- I don't… - Kid，don't lie to me.
我是个警察 我知道你在说谎！他们到底是什么人？
I'm a cop。I can tell you're lying。Who were they？
好吧！好吧 好吧…
OK。OK，OK.
他们和我各自工作 为第三方服务
They were my competition.
在下一个口右转到康卡街
Make the next right onto Concord.
那个第三方说他们是个软件公司 刚发明出一种新的加密算法
They said they'd developed a mutating encryption algorithm
想看看它到底能不能被破解
and they wanted to see if it could be cracked.
我做个就是这个 我…我负责数学部分的安全工作
That's what I do。I do math-based security.
听着 我正在想… 如果你想实施像末世入侵这样 庞大又变态的计划
Here's the thing。To pull off something as massive and crazy as a fire sale，
就需要成千上万的人来编程序 但要安装运行的话 只要几个黑客就可以搞定了
you need tons of guys to write programs，but only a few Black Hats to implement it.
而到那时 那些做最初工作的人 那些实际上没有做错什么事的人 比如说我…
At that point the start-up guys，who haven't really done anything wrong，like me…
就会落得跟墙上照片上那些人一样的下场
Would end up as pictures on some guy's wall.
我向上帝发誓 麦克连… 我向你发誓 我真的不知道会…
I swear to God，McClane，I swear to you I had no idea I was gonna be…
把整个世界送上不归路
an accessory to Armageddon.
在下一个路口左转到列克星顿
Take the next left at Lexington.
那声音可真性感 她干嘛要让我们走这条路？
And that's a sexy voice。What's she taking us this way for？
- 510小队 - 哦 上帝
- Unit 510。- Oh，my God.
请为两辆联邦调查局的车子清出道路 他们正在前往康卡街
Clear a route for two FBI vehicles approaching on Concord.
收到 马上行动
Copy，dispatch.
就是她
That's her.
- 她是谁？- 你在说什么呢？
- Her who？- What are you talking about？
- 是他们 - 你说的“他们”是哪个？
- It's them。- You're saying it's them them？
我向你发誓我绝对认识她 不管到哪儿我都认得出这个声音
I swear to you I know her。I would know her voice anywhere.
- 别 什么也别说… - 你先把嘴闭上一会儿
- No，don't say anything… - Just keep your mouth shut for a minute.
嘿 交警局的 你们那边今天还好吗？
Hey，Metro，how's your day goin' over there？
接到那么多举报电话 挺手忙脚乱的吧？
Gotta be pretty crazy over there，what with all those 587s，huh？
是的 警官 我们已经全员出动了！
Yes，sir。We've had to dispatch all units.
你们全员出动 就为了那些光着身子 到处走的疯子吗？
You had to dispatch all units for all the naked people walking around？
少说废话了 宝贝儿 叫你老板过来
Cut the bullshit，honey，and just put your boss on.
罗夫林 我们得离开这条路 左转到十四号大街
Laughlin，we're getting off this route。Turn left on 14th Street.
- 麦克连警官！- 是麦克连探员 混蛋！
- Officer McClane。- It's Detective McClane，asshole.
别担心 等哪天我到监狱去看你时 咱们有的是时间来互相认识
Don't worry。We'll have plenty of time to get to know each other when I visit you in prison.
但是 约翰！我已经知道很多关于你的事了
But，John，I already know so much about you.
你在布鲁克林的住址
Your address in Brooklyn，
你房屋抵押贷款的偿还情况 还有你在纽约警局呆了几年
the payments on your mortgage，how long you've been a member of the NYPD.
对了 霍利还好吗？
And how's Holly？
哦 真可怜！你们已经离婚了！小露西和杰克是不是很难过？
Oh，that's sad。You're divorced。Was that tough on little Jack and Lucy？
这个更可怜！都三十年了 我还以为你的退休金储备 能比现在更丰厚一点儿呢
Now，this is sad。After 30 years I thought you'd have a better pension plan annuity.
哦 现在情况变得更糟了
Oh，and it gets worse.
你那四十万零一千块钱都没了
Your 401k no longer exists.
- 这样吧 让我来补偿你 - 在那个十字路口堵上他们
- Tell you what。Let me make it up to you。- Box them in at that intersection.
杀了法瑞尔 然后开车走人
Shoot Mr Farrell in the head and drive away，
等你开到下一个街区末的时候
and by the time you reach the end of the next block
你的一切债务将被全部清零 而你孩子们也将一辈子不用发愁了
all your debts will be wiped clean and your children will be set for life.
这些条件的确很诱人 尤其是最后那个
Now，that really is tempting，especially that last part，
但我想我只能拒绝了 你个混蛋
but I think I'm gonna have to pass，jerk-off.
约翰！你的思想真是太落伍了 跟这个时代格格不入
John，you're a Timex watch in a digital age.
你会一败涂地的
You're gonna lose.
是啊 还有一个可能就是我找到你
Yeah，well，the other thing that could happen is I could come and find you，
揍你一顿然后砸了你们的派对 你看怎么样 呆子？
kick your ass and throw you out of your own party。What about that？
待在那里别离开
Hold your position.
他不回话了！
He's not responding.
趴下！快趴下！
Get down！Get right down！
别起来！
Just stay down！
有警官在政府大楼拐角遇袭中枪了 重复 有警官中枪了！
Officers down at the corner of Main and Constitution。Officers down！
快 快出来！咱们走！
Come on，come on，get out！Let's go！
他妈的！趴下！
Goddammit！Just stay down！
趴下！抓紧了！
Get down！Just hang on！
呼叫总部 我们一辆警车起火了 请求支援！
Base，we've got a squad car under fire！We need backup！
这里是总部 我们正派出增援警力
This is base。We're sending backup.
自己小心
Just brace yourself.
抓紧！抓紧…
Hang on.
坚持住
耶！
Oh，yeah！
- 目标逃脱了 - 继续跟着他们！
- We lost the tail。- Stay with them.
- 他们又来了 - 我知道
- They're back。- I know.
走隧道！左边 左边！
Take the tunnel。Left！
上帝呀 你要干嘛…
God，what are you… Oh，God！
把那个隧道的结构图调出来
Bring up the schematics on that tunnel.
隧道结构图！
The tunnel！
把北边入口打开
Open the gates on the north side entrance.
重新安排车行方向 开放所有车道
Redirect traffic to occupy all lanes.
- 把另一边入口也打开 - 什么？
- Now open the other side。- What？
起开！
Move！
抓好了…
Hang onto something.
嘿！别下车！嘿！别…
Hey！Don't get out of the car！Hey！Don't…
呆在那儿！站着别动！
Just stay there！Stand still！
快跑！快跑！
Run。Run！
哦 上帝！
Oh，God！
以后别再像刚才那样犹豫了
Don't hesitate like that again.
- 你没事吧？- 没事 没事
- You all right？- Yeah，yeah.
- 呆在这儿 就在这儿等我一会儿 - 什么？！
- Just stay here。Stay right here for a minute。- What？！
“我不能随便找个便衣 约翰！不行”
「It can't be a uniform，John。No.」
站到墙那边去 先生！“联邦调查局的人打电话来要求协助”
Get over to the wall，sir！「Feds called in a favour.」
“你只要到泽西接个孩子 开车送他去华盛顿就行了”
「All you gotta do is go pick up a kid down in Jersey，drive him down to DC.」
“这能有什么难的呢 嗯？不可能有那么难的 是吧？”
「How hard can that be，huh？It can't be that hard，can it？」
“不行 一定得是个高级探员”
「No，gotta be a senior detective.」
你以为把路堵住 冲着我扔几辆车 就能拦住我吗？嗯？
Think a traffic jam，throwing a car at me's gonna stop me？Huh？
兰德 到里面把事情搞定
Rand，get in there and get it done.
没必要了 他朝我们开过来了
真不是个好主意！
This is not a good idea.
- 别碰我 别碰我 - 好 好 对不起 对不起
- Don't touch me，don't touch me。- OK，sorry，sorry.
你没事吧？哦 上帝！
Are you OK？Oh，my God！
- 运气不赖 打得挺准 是吧？- 噢 是 是很幸运 真是…
- Pretty lucky shot，huh？- Oh，yeah，lucky。That was…
你竟然用汽车把直升机给打下来了
You just killed a helicopter with a car.
我不是没子弹了么
I was out of bullets.
- 你怎么样？- 膝盖破了点皮 还有点儿犯哮喘…
- How you doin'？- I skinned my knee，my asthma's acting up…
- 管他什么呢 我没事！- 拉我一把 以后可千万别从车上跳下来
- Whatever。Yeah，I'm fine。- Give me a hand。Don'tjump outta cars.
兰德 回答！
Rand，check in.
直升机被毁了
那法瑞尔和麦克连呢？
What about Farrell and McClane？
说来话长了
快回来！
Come back in.
好 我们继续行动 进入第三阶段！
OK，we're moving on。Begin stage three.
我刚跟艾默森通过话 他的人已经到乌德隆了
I just spoke to Emerson。The team's arriving at Woodlawn now.
很好！麻衣 准备下载数据
Very good。Mai，get ready for the downloads.
请出示证件
ID，sir.
把车停在后面 我们带你进去
Park behind the transpo。We'll lead you in.
看好前门！你跟我来！
Man the gate。You're with me.
只有五楼以上才解除了炭疽警报 要到下面楼层的话得通过国防部的身份验证
Anthrax alarms only went off on five floors。Below that you'll need DOD clearance.
真不知道你们为什么要到下面去 那里除了服务器之外什么都没有
I don't know why you'd need to go further。There's nothin' down there but servers.
再说一遍 罗德里格斯！我没有听清
Go again。Rodriguez！I didn't copy.
- 已控制前门！- 收到
- Gate secured。- Copy.
好 我们进去了
OK，we are in.
这太疯狂了
This is insane.
嘿！嘿 这简直是荒唐
Hey！Hey，this is absurd.
哥们儿 这是很坚强 可也很愚蠢 你得去医院 看看你都什么样了
Man，there's tough and there's stupid。You gotta go to a hospital。Look at you.
我虽然不是个医生 但你看起来的确是受伤了
I'm not a doctor，but you're hurt.
- 是啊 看上去蛮性感的是吗？- 才不呢！
- Yeah。Sexy，right？- No！
走吧
Come on.
我们需要的不是医生 是警察！
We don't need a doctor。We need the cops.
他进去了！
He's in.
让一让！拜托借个过 快走
Get outta the way！Make a hole，please。Come on.
小心！不好意思 不好意思！快过来
Watch out！Excuse me！Excuse me！Come on.
纽约警局的 看到吗？我带着这孩子 来 我们走 孩子
NYPD。All right？I got this kid。Come on。Let's go，kid.
劳驾 谢谢
Excuse me。Thanks.
纽约警局的 纽约警局的
NYPD。NYPD.
过来
Coming through.
警官！
Sergeant？
警官！我得跟你谈一下
Sergeant！I need to speak to you.
- 医务人员在后面 - 我没事 我是纽约警局的 得跟你谈谈！
- The medic's in the back。- I'm all right。NYPD。I need to talk to you.
就一会儿
Just give me a minute.
警官！
Sergeant！
哦 上帝！
Oh，my God.
咱们走吧
Let's get outta here.
服务器已经准备好了
Siamo pronti.
可以开始了
We're a go.
开始下载
Launch the downloads.
- 什么也没有啊 - 耐心点
- Nothing's happening。- Be patient.
- 我不清楚 可它就是没反应 - 再等等
- I don't know。It's not responding。- Wait for it.
看到了？这不就开始了
See？There you go.
- 下到20% 时通知我 - 好的
- Tell me when the download reaches 20%。- OK.
请让一下
Excuse me.
- 请让一下！谢谢 - 真见鬼
- Excuse me！Thank you。- Holy shit.
- 孩子？嘿！- 在 在
- Kid？Kid，hey！- Yeah，yeah.
- 你那包里有电话吗？- 有
- You got a phone in that bag？- Yeah.
来 咱们走
Come on。Let's go.
这个给你 特工姓名…多瓦雷克 就是你了
And here you go，Agent… Tovarek。Guess that's you.
- 已经下到20% 了 - 该行动了
- Download's at 20%。- Time to move.
让他们继续首尾难顾吧
Let's keep them chasing their tails.
由于近期发生的各种事件 执法人员已提高了警戒
Due to recent activity，law enforcement agencies are being cautious.
他们让驾车人离开车子 接受检查后方可返回
They are telling drivers to abandon their vehicles until they are searched.
并且大家还可以看到 警犬队正在对每一辆车子进行检查
And，as you can see，canine units are checking each vehicle.
现在的状况到底是和我们先前听到的 炭疽病毒警报有关
Whether this is connected to the anthrax reports we heard earlier
还是一起新的恐怖事件 我们现在还不得而知…
or a new terrorist threat，we do not know…
- 联邦航空局已停止了所有航班 - 很好！
- FAAjust grounded all flights。- Good.
长官 我们现在可以接通进入所有的网络系统了 通信、电力、供水、核能系统…
We have complete access over networks，phones，power grids，water，nuclear.
- 嘿 不好意思… - 扎克·巴勒 国家安全局的
- Hey，excuse me。- Jack Parry，NSA.
查克·萨姆 来自国土安全部联络处 我们是白宫派来的
Chuck Summer，DHS liaison。White House made the call.
- 有什么需要吗？我们是来帮忙的 - 帮忙？哇 太棒了
- Anything you need，we're here to help。- Help？Wow，that's great.
我们的人需要点空间工作 能给我们腾个地方吗？
We're gonna need some work space for our people。What can you do for us？
你都看到了 我们现在正使用这地方 而你们呢 可以站到那边角落里…负责联络
As you can see，we're using the space，so you guys can stand in the corner and… liaise.
如果我需要你们帮忙 会招手叫你们的
If I need something，I'll just wave to you.
- 等一下 不…不要打电话！- 什么？为什么？你在说什么？
- Wait！No，don't call。- What are you talkin' about？
他们可能早就入侵了通讯网络 如果你用了它 他们就会找到我们 把电话放一边儿吧
They probably cracked that hours ago。They could trace us。Put it away.
- 你确定？- 是的！
- You sure？- Yes.
或者…砸了它也行 嘿 没必要真砸了呀
Or… smash it。You didn't have to smash it.
- 对不起！对不起 是警方紧急事件！- 嘿！
- Excuse me。It's a police emergency。- Hey！
他会再打给你的
He'll call you right back.
来 就在这儿 到这里来！
Here，right in here。Come here.
- 有信号吗？- 有
- You got a signal？- Yeah.
- 喂！- 是约翰·麦克连 找伯曼警官
- Yeah。- This is John McClane for Agent Bowman.
长官 是约翰·麦克连的来电
Sir，John McClane is on the line.
- 麦克连 说吧！- 我们没能到国土安全部
- McClane，go。- We never made it to DHS.
他们又来追杀那小子 你的人都死了
They came after the kid again。All your men are down.
- 法瑞尔呢？- 他现在和我在一起
- What about Farrell？- I got him with me right now.
- 长官！- 约翰 等一下！
- Sir？- Hang on，John.
好 我等着
Yeah，I'll hold on.
真是“天堂无路”啊
Another day in paradise.
他们侵入了所有的一切 整个通讯系统 电话 移动通讯 广播卫星…
They just swarmed into everything，the telecom system，phones，cells，satellites.
他们屏蔽了所有电视台
They're blanketing every station.
（如果这个只是开始呢？）
（如果你受伤了 独自一人 打911也没人接你电话呢？）
- 可以拨回新闻台吗？- 这就是新闻台
- Can you put the news back on？- This is the news.
- 每个台都在播这个 - 已经好几分钟都是这样了
- It's on every channel。- Been this way for a few minutes now.
（如果你永远得不到帮助呢？）
我的天啊！
Oh，my God.
麦克连？
McClane！
当心！
Look out.
Look out！
小心
Look out.
伯曼！伯曼 你看到了吗？
Bowman？Bowman，do you see that？
伯曼 那是假的！
Bowman，it's a fake.
我看到了
I see it.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
哦 该死！
Oh，shit.
- 麦克连？- 伯曼！
- McClane？- Bowman！
卫星信号中断了 给我一部有线电话
Satellite's down。Get me a land line.
我只写了一小段代码 却毁了整个世界 这简直就是一场恐怖袭击
I wrote one little piece of code and the world falls apart。This is virtual terrorism.
- 什么？- 我知道听起来很疯狂
- What？- You know，it's crazy.
我第一次听说末世入侵这回事的时候
The first time I heard of the concept of a fire sale
自己还想如果有人真做得到 应该会很酷
I actually thought it would be cool if anyone ever really did it.
只要按一下重启键 就可以搞砸整个系统来玩玩
Just hit the reset button and melt the system just for fun.
喂！这不是什么系统 是整个国家
Hey，it's not a system。It's a country.
我们现在说的是人 一整个国家的人
You're talkin' about people，a whole country full of people，
孤独地坐在家中 吓得半死 明白吗！
sitting at home alone，scared to death in their houses，all right？
所以别再回忆你那些过去的时光了 想想怎么帮我抓到这些人
So finish your nostalgic moment and think a little bit and help me catch these guys.
帮帮我 站在他们的立场上好好想想
Just help me。Just put yourself in their shoes.
来吧 如果是你在做末世入侵行动 你下一步会做什么？
Come on。If this were your fire sale，what would be your next move？
好吧！嗯… 末世入侵的关键就在于它大部分都是远程操作的 对吧？
OK，uh，well，the whole point of a fire sale is that it's mostly done by remote，right？
但不是什么东西都可以网上控制的… 主要的公用设施就不是
But not everything is run completely online。Major utilities aren't.
它们由闭路系统运行 所以虽然你可以破坏它的安全系统
They're run by closed circuits，so you could breach the security，
但要彻底关闭它 就得亲自跑一趟 要到那里才行
but to shut it down you'd have to physically go there。You'd have to show up.
还有 还有…
And，uh…
- 把那人的掌上电脑给我 - 电话都死机了 不运作了
- Give me that guy's PDA。- Phones are all dead.
不 电话没事 只是网络中断了 我只要从新设置一下 把它连到老的 卫星通讯系统上就可以了
No，it's the network that's dead。I've just gotta reprogram it and link it into the old Satcoms.
黑客们常用那个网络 大概那群家伙也在用它来相互沟通呢
Hackers surf 'em all the time。Probably what these guys are using to talk to each other.
你是怎么知道这些东西的？
How do you know all this stuff？
老兄 我也不知道 那里有很多 乱七八糟的东西 我不能告诉你
Dude，I don't know。There's a lot rattling around up there。I couldn't tell you.
好了 这是国家能源分布网
OK。National power grid.
燃气跟电力设施分布在三个地区 东部 中部和西部
Gas and electric is divided into three zones，Eastern，Central，Western…
每个地区都有一台主力交换机
each with a primary hub.
就在这里
Here it is.
- 那我们现在看到的是？- 东部的交换机
- What are we looking at？- That is the Eastern hub.
如果他们把那个关掉 整个东海岸就会断电了
Now，they take this out，wipes out all the power for the entire Eastern Corridor.
但还是那句话 他们一定得亲自到那儿 手动去做
But，again，you'd have to do it manually.
- 好吧 来 我们走！- 什么？去西维吉尼亚？
- OK。Come on。Let's go。- What？To West Virginia？
我真的认为自己已经无法忍受再被人追杀了 麦克连 麦克连？
I honestly don't think I can handle any more people trying to kill me。McClane！
- 你会习惯的 - 麦克连！哦 该死！
- You get used to it。- McClane。Oh，shit.
长官 所有的无线网络都瘫痪了 而且他们可能还正在入侵地面网络系统
Sir，wireless networks are down and I think they're hitting the land lines，too.
我不管你用什么方法 一定要给我找到一条可用的线路
I don't care how，you find me a line.
- 说吧 你们有什么发现？- 我们已经排查了整幢大楼 没有任何问题
- Come on，what you got？- We swept the building。Seems clean.
- 我们可以再查一遍 可我想应该找不到什么… - 不用了 不用了！
- We can sweep it again… - Don't bother。Don't bother.
这是个假象 那家伙在耍我们
It's a fake。This guy's playin' us.
好了 让所有的人回到紧急中心里去
OK，get everyone back inside the crisis centre now.
打开通道！
OK，let's open it up！
- 快 上车！- 门锁了
- Come on，get in。- Door's locked.
除非你还有一把枪 这样我可以用它来开门
Unless you have an extra gun I can use to unlock it.
嘿 嘿 别那样！你这样车就不能用了！
Hey。Hey，don't do that！You're gonna disable it.
上帝！
Jesus Christ！
真疯狂 你看到了吗？
That was crazy。Did you see that？
对不起 老兄 我不知道它那么快就出来了
Sorry about that，man。I didn't know it'd come out so fast.
天 这还真是够麻烦的 你是怎么把它弄下来的？
Man，this is a pain in the ass。How'd you do yours？
你没事吧？是不是被撞到了？
You all right？What？Did it hit you a little bit？
对不起
Sorry.
不 等一下 别碰那些 好吗？我知道我在做什么 我以前也干过这个
No，please don't touch those，OK？I know what I'm doing。I've done this before.
我是说 读到过这个…
I mean，I've read about it.
道路协助中心 我们侦测到您车子的安全气囊已被释放
RoadAssist。We've detected an air-bag deployment.
是的…拜托你 我们刚撞上了一棵树 而我…我爸现在心脏病发作了
Yes… Please，we just hit a tree and my… my dad is having a heart attack.
我觉得他要死了 求你帮帮忙
I think he's gonna die。You need to help us.
请稍等 我们会给您联系急救服务的
Hold while we contact emergency services.
不 不用！他快死了！听着 我可以送他去医院 我能开车 我现在很好
No，no！He's dying！I can get him to a hospital。I can drive。I'm fine.
但我就是扭不动钥匙 无法发动车子 你可以帮我发动吗？求求你了 老爸呀…
But I can't really turn the key，so you gotta start the car for us，OK？Please，Dad…
- 请问您的名字是？- 我叫…
- Your name，please？- I'm…
我的名字是…法兰克！
My name is… Frank，
我爸的名字 嗯 是…
and my dad's name is，um… is…
是…佛洛克·瑟金斯基
Dvorak… Tsajanski.
拜托 帮帮我们就好 我们需要你的帮助 求求你了
Please… Please，just help us。We need your help。Please.
救护车已经上路 马上就到
Emergency services are on their way.
别 等一下 听着 女士… 你叫什么名字？
No，no，listen to me。Ma'am，what is your name？
- 桃丽丝 - 桃丽丝？
- Dolores。- Dolores？
好吧 桃丽丝！我不知道你还有没有爸爸 但我有
OK，Dolores，I don't know if you have a dad，but I do，
而且我希望明年的今天他依然健在
and I wanna be able to say that a year from now.
因为我的父亲他是我的英雄 而现在他就在我的怀中 奄奄一息
Because my dad is my hero，and right now he is in my arms dying，
他唯一的希望就是马上被送到医院 我们实在是不能等了
and his only hope is to get to a hospital right now。We can't wait.
所以求求你快把这该死的车发动起来！
So please start the goddamn car！
谢谢你 桃丽丝！
Thank you，Dolores.
把掌上电脑给我 我要联系“法师”
Pass the PDA。I gotta call the Warlock.
- 谁？- “法师” 他是个电脑奇才
- The what？- The Warlock。A digital Jedi。He's amazing.
（西维吉尼亚州 东部电力交换中心）
- 小姐 你无权进入这里 - 联邦调查局 我们怀疑这里有安全漏洞
- Ma'am，you're not authorised to be here。- FBI。We suspect a security breach.
未经许可 你不能在这里降落…
You can't land here without authorisa…
（欢迎来到西维吉尼亚）
刚才干得漂亮 小子！
That was pretty good back there，kid.
谢谢
Thanks.
你怎么了？没的可抱怨的了？
What's the matter with you？Nothing else to complain about？
不 我只是…
No。I'm just…
- 那是什么？你怎么了？- 我不像你 我 我做不了这种事
- Well，what？What's the matter you？- I'm not like you。I can't do this shit.
这是什么意思？像我什么？
What's that mean？Like what？
我不像是那种…那种英雄人物 无所不能什么的 我不像你那么勇敢
I'm not，like，heroic and everything。I'm not brave like you are.
- 我不是那种人 - 我可不是什么英雄 孩子
- I'm not that guy。- I'm nobody's hero，kid.
你在过去的六小时内 已经救了我不下十次了
You've saved my life，like，ten times in six hours.
我只是在做自己的工作 仅此而已
Just doing my job，that's all.
知道做英雄能得到什么好处吗？什么都没有 只有挨枪子儿
Know what you get for being a hero？Nothing。You get shot at.
别人会拍拍你的肩膀 称赞你几句 等等等等 哦 拜托！
You get a little pat on the back，blah-blah-blah。Attaboy.
然后离婚
You get divorced.
老婆都不记得你姓什么
A wife that can't remember your last name.
孩子们不想跟你说话
Your kids don't wanna talk to you.
自己一个人吃饭 没个人陪
You get to eat a lot of meals by yourself.
老实说 孩子 没人想成为这种人
Trust me，kid，nobody wants to be that guy.
- 那为什么你还要做这些事情？- 因为现在没有其他人愿意做
- Then why are you doin' this？- Cos there's nobody else to do it right now.
相信我 如果真有其他人肯做 我绝对会让他们去做
If there was somebody else to do it，I would let them do it.
但现在没有 所以只能我们来做
But there's not。So we're doin' it.
哎
Ah.
这就是你为什么会成为现在这样喽
And that's what makes you that guy.
到目前为止一切顺利
Thing's flying now.
联系艾默森 告诉他我们很快就到
Contact Emerson。Tell him we'll be there soon.
你们在这里做什么？这一层是禁止…
What the hell are you doing？This whole floor's restricted acc…
待在这儿
Stay here.
快 跟我来
All right，come on.
- 我们进去了 - 很好 把它关闭
- We're in。- Good。Shut it down.
（启动手动关闭程序）
看来你说得没错 小子
Guess you were right，kid.
呃…这的确…很糟
OK，that's… awful.
有人来了
We got company.
- 他们要怎样才能关闭整个电网？- 什么？
- How would they shut down a power grid？- What？
- 快点 - 呃…中央控制室
- Come on。- Uh… Central control room。OK…
- 在四楼！四楼！- 走！
- Uh，fourth floor。Fourth floor。- Come on.
你走右边
You take the right.
哦 该死
Oh，shit.
嘘…
Shh.
- 我们能不能停… - 尽量跟上来
- Can we stop for… - Try to keep up.
我在跟着你！我只是想休息一下喘口气
I am！I just wanna stop for two seconds to catch our breath.
你知道有健身房这种东西吗？
You know，they have these things called gymnasiums.
快 咱们走 走！
Come on，let's go。Let's go.
情报显示这些恐怖分子是具有移动性的
Intel's fairly certain the terrorists are mobile.
因此我们才无法利用三角定位找到他们 这是他们唯一的方法
It's the only way to avoid signal triangulation.
考虑到他们要运行大量硬件设备
With the amount of hardware they're running，
目标应该是在大型运输车辆当中 极有可能是货柜车
we're probably looking for a large vehicle，most likely a semitrailer rig.
很好 告诉国土安全局的那帮人
All right。Tell the guys at Homeland Security
说我们需要他们所有的人力 卫星及可运行的网络 现在就要
we need every agent，satellite and functioning network they got。Now.
（电力关闭程序 95%的发电机组已经可以关闭 是否继续？）
游戏时间结束了 甜心
Play time's over，sweetheart.
别乱来
Don't.
把手从枪上拿开 把手举起来！
Take your hand off the gun。Hands up.
站起来
Stand up.
去呀 快！
Go on。Now！
去吧 小子 看你的了
Let's go，kid。You're up.
好…
OK…
越快越好
As fast as you can.
天！
Jesus！
我已经受够了这他妈的功夫！
That's enough of this kung fu shit.
我以前也碰过别的母狗 但你可能是最凶的一只…
I've known some bitches in my day，but you are maybe the…
这拳怎么样 呃？
Still awake，huh？
- 继续做你的 - 好
- Just keep doin' what you're doin'。- OK.
- 你还需要多久？- 嗯…用不了多久
- How much time do you need？- Um… Not much.
喔
Whoo.
- 好了么？- 我 嗯…
- Are you done？- I，uh…
- 好了没有？- 不 还没
- Are you done？- No，not quite.
- 什么？- 这可不像收取信件那么简单
- What？- I'm not exactly checking my email here.
他们已经进入了虚拟模式 我现在 要断开他们接入的系统功能接口 重启主机
They used VM mode，so I'm isolating their API and booting the host.
- 什么？！- 就是说我需要30秒钟时间 行了吗？
- What？！- It means about 30 seconds，OK？
做这事可不简单 尤其是在…
Not the easiest thing to do when…
好 好…
OK…
把你刚才所做的事全部撤销 快！
Undo everything you just did。Now！
好 好 好
OK。OK，OK.
我是右撇子 右撇子 我得用我的右手 真的
I'm a righty，I'm a righty。I need my other hand，I really do.
我是右撇子
I'm a righty.
（员工专用停车场）
只剩最后一步了…
One last door to open.
你知道你在做什么吗？你知道这样做会给国家造成什么后果吗？
Do you know what you're doing？Do you realise what this'll do to the country？
是的 我知道 快点儿干！
Yes，I do。Now open the door.
好 很好 很高兴我们有相同的认知
OK，good。Glad we're on the same page.
你都知道？很高兴你能知道这些
You do？I'm glad you know.
你还好吗？
How you doin'？
抓好了
Hang on.
听着 我们能不能好好谈谈…
Listen，let's just talk about this for one second.
感觉怎么样？还不是太紧吧 呃？
How you doin'？That's not too tight，is it？
该死！
Damn it！
再吃我一拳！
Smile pretty！
麦克连！
McClane！
妈的
Shit.
麦克连 快出来！
McClane，get out of there！
快点 伙计 快点！
Come on，man！Come on！
快！
Come on，man.
你刚看到了吗？
Did you see that？
那你把他们做的都停下来了 对吗？
So you stopped it，right？
是 是 是 不过你知道 当有一把枪指着你时做事会更难专心
You know，a gun to your head makes it harder to do this kind of work.
- 什么？- 我就知道你是这种反应
- What？- I know that comes as a surprise.
- 你就不能把它关掉？或者锁住？- 我也不确定
- Can't you just turn it off？Lock 'em out？- I'm not sure.
不过我也许能拖延些时间
I might be able to slow 'em down，though.
西部和中部的电力转换中心都是我们的了 现在就等麻衣那边了
Western and Central hubs are ours。We're just waiting on Mai's end.
等等 不太对劲 所有的安全系统又重新启动了
Hang on。Something's up。All the security's reactivating.
我想有人可能想买点儿便宜的伟哥哦 那就给你来点儿广告吧
I think someone might be in the market for some cheap Viagra.
既然你码子已经死了 干嘛不上性感单身族网站 找个美眉聊天呢？
Now your girlfriend's dead，why don't you check out our sexy singles？
是个电子炸弹
It's an e-bomb.
嘿…
Hey…
好吧 等一下 等一下
All right，wait，wait.
（正在跟踪远程通讯）
- 麻衣 回话 发生了什么事？- 麻衣？
- Mai，talk to me。What's going on？- Mai？
喔 对 就是那个爱踢人的亚洲小妞儿？
Oh，yeah，little Asian chick，likes to kick people？
我看她得很长时间都无法再跟任何人说话了
I don't think she's gonna be talking to anybody for a really long time.
我上次看到她时 她还在电梯升降道的底部 被一台休旅车撞得稀巴烂呢
Last time I saw her，she was at the bottom of an elevator shaft with an SUV up her ass.
怎么啦？说不出话来了？
What's the matter？Cat got your tongue？
听着 蠢蛋 你的末世入侵行动已经结束了
Listen，jackass。Your fire sale is over.
把你的那个小杂耍团收拾收拾滚吧 否则我会去找你 然后好好修理你
Just pack up your little circus or I'm gonna come and I'm gonna kick your ass.
你根本不知道我是谁 我的能力有多大
You have no idea who I am or what I'm capable of.
等我把这里的事结束以后… 我保证用不了多久…
When I'm finished here，and I promise it'll be soon.
我会全心全力地对付你
I will focus all my attention… on you.
你想把这事儿弄成私人恩怨？好 奉陪到底
You wanna make things personal，fine.
调整所有的天然气输送方向 统统给我转到东部中心
Reroute every cubic foot of natural gas in the pipelines to that station.
- 你能用这个联络到伯曼么？- 当然可以 联络任何人都没问题
- Can you get Bowman on this thing？- Sure。I can get anyone on it.
那就快联系他
Do it.
- 就现在？- 对 就现在
- Now？- Yeah，now.
拜托 不要啊
Please，no.
- 是汤玛斯·盖布尔 - 妈的
- It's Thomas Gabriel。- Shit.
- 你认识这家伙？- 我和他共事过
- You know this guy？- I worked with him.
他本来是国防部内部安全系统的主程序员
He was DOD's chief programmer for infrastructure security.
9/11事件后 他告知众参谋长 国防安全系统有弱点 极易被攻击
After 9/11，he's the guy that told Joint Chiefs the system was vulnerable.
他想要整个系统做彻底检修 但他们不听 盖布尔可并不是那种好脾气 待人友善的人
He wanted an overhaul，but they wouldn't listen。Gabriel's not people-friendly.
你也这么看？
You think so？
当他企图公开这一切时 他们毁了他
When he tried to go public，they crucified him.
毁掉了他的名誉 冻结了他的财产… 那之后他就消失了
Destroyed his reputation，froze assets。After that he disappeared.
我们有个蛮严重的问题
We got a pretty serious problem.
等一下…什么事？
Hold on one minute。What？
我看我们需要马上离开这里
I think we need to get out of here right now.
- 他们正把天然气导向这里 - 天然气？什么天然气？
- They're sending the gas lines here。- Gas lines？What gas lines？
上帝！
Christ.
噢 所有的天然气 看到那些闪烁的箭头了吗？情况非常不妙
Oh… all of them。See that，those flashing arrows？That's not good.
- 所有那些都朝这里来了？- 对 我想我们得走了
- All that's coming here？- Yeah。I think we gotta go.
听好 我们必需要走了 你快去找盖布尔
Listen，I gotta go。Just find Thomas Gabriel.
麦克连？麦克连？
McClane？McClane？
咱们走了 快点搞定！
Let's go。Finish this up.
马上走！快弄完 快点！走吧！
Right now。Finish it up，come on！Let's go！
进去！进去！
Get in there！
你没事吧？
You OK？
- 快 我们得出去 - 有什么意义呢？这到底有什么意义？
- Let's go。We gotta get outta here。- What is the point？Man，what is the point？
嘿 别闹了 快点
Hey，knock that off，come on.
这些跟你帮他们写的代码有关 快 好好想想 帮助咱们取胜
This has something to do with that code you wrote for them。Think。Come on，help us win.
取胜？我们什么时候开始取胜了 呃？
Win？When do we start winning？Huh？
你看看周围 你疯了吗？我们看起来像是要取胜的样子吗？
Look around。Are you out of your mind？Does it look like we're close to winning？
我们刚刚被修理得很惨哪！
We just got the shit kicked out of us！
你以为我还瞒着你什么吗？以为我还有什么没告诉你吗？
You think I'm holding out on you？
如果我知道他们想要什么 我会告诉你的！我会很乐意地告诉你的！
If I knew what they wanted，I would tell you！I would happily tell you！
上帝！
Jesus.
“法师”…“法师”…
The Warlock。The Warlock.
哦 太棒了！妈的 手机也没用了
Oh，great。Ah！There goes the cellphone.
- 他们把卫星都从天上打下来了吗？- 不 是电池没电了
- They knocked satellites out of the skies？- No，your battery ran out.
- 对了 我们应该去见他 - 谁？
- We should go see him。- Who？
“法师”啊 我们可以开车去他家 就在巴尔的摩
The Warlock。We should drive to his house in Baltimore.
- 我现在才不要去什么“法师”家 - 嘿！你想要我帮你 我这就是在帮你
- Can't go to the Warlock's house now。- Hey！This is me helping you.
明白吗？相信我 我们必须去找法师 这是我们唯一的希望
OK？Trust me。We gotta go see the Warlock。That's our only hope.
- 你喜欢飞行吗？- 嗯 你说什么？就像是和飞行员一起吗？
- How do you feel about flying？- Uh，about what？Like，with a pilot？
- 把它插进那“圆型的”东西里就行了 - 什么“棕色的”东西？（二者发音相似）
- Just stick it in the round thing。- What brown thing？
喏 把这个戴上
Here，put these on.
把它插进去就好了 这样就行了
Just stick it in there。That'll work.
- 你还好吧？- 还好 只是有点怕飞行
- You OK？- Uh，yeah，I'm just kind of afraid of flying.
- 我以前也对飞行怕得要死 - 真的？
- I used to be terrified of flying。- Really？
对啊 我还上了些课 诸如“直面恐惧”之类的
Yeah。I took some lessons。Face your fears，that kind of thing.
- 是吗？有用吗？- 没什么用
- Yeah？Did it help？- Not really.
- 它应该发出这种声音吗？- 嗯
- Is it supposed to make that sound？- Yeah.
- 也许我们应该开车去 就像在马路上兜风那样… - 放松点 起飞可是最难的
- Maybe we should just drive。- Take it easy。Taking off's the hardest part.
是吗？我听说…
Really？I heard…
- 说实话 我错过了几节飞行课 - 哈哈哈！真的吗？
- To be honest，I missed a couple of classes。- Ha，ha，ha！You did？Really？
但你还是有执照的吧？我是说 你还是可以真正开飞机什么的吧？
But you have your licence，right？I mean，you can fly one of these things？
- 哦 上帝！- 嘿嘿 出发！我们起飞了
- Oh，God。- Hey-hey，here we go！We're up.
上帝！
Oh，God.
很好 还蛮好的嘛
That's good。That's pretty good.
天啊 你看 这整个地区都是漆黑一片
Jesus，look at that。This whole area's blacked out.
我们怎么才能找到“法师”的家？
How we gonna find Warlock's house？
嗯 应该就是依然还亮着灯的那家吧
Um，it's probably gonna be the one with the lights still on.
断电正在不断蔓延 大约一半的东海岸地区已经停电了
Power outage keeps spreading。About half the East Coast has already gone down.
好吧 把所有东西都接到应急发电机上
All right。Put everything on emergency generators.
他们到底是怎么突破我们防线的？
How the hell are they getting past us？
好 就在那下面 在那下面 我看到了
OK。Down there，down there。I see it.
- 在那下面？- 往左 下去
- Down there？- Left。Down.
什么？我们就在那儿降落吗？
What？Are we gonna land down there？
- 好 抓紧了 - 好 好 哦！
- All right，hang on。- OK，OK。Ohhh！
小心栅栏！栅栏！
Fence。Fence。Fence！
- 栅栏！看着点儿栅栏！- 我看到了
- Fence。Fence！- I see it.
小心…
Watch…
哦！
Ow！Ohhh！
- 天哪！- 走吧
- Oh，Jesus。- Come on.
哦 没错 没错 “起飞可是最困难的”
Oh，yeah。Oh，「Taking off's the hardest part.」
咱们走吧
Let's go.
好吧 关于法师 有件事你必须要了解 他很恨警察 真的很恨
Now，there's something you need to know about Warlock。He hates cops，OK？
所以让我来跟他说话就好了 明白？
So just let me do all the talking，OK？
见鬼！
Shit.
嘿 卡鲁迪斯太太
Hey，Mrs Kaludis.
嗯 弗来迪在家吗？
Um，is Freddy home？
我是马特·法瑞尔 这位是 嗯…
I'm Matt Farrell and this is，uh…
比利
Billy.
我们是他朋友…太空夏令营的朋友 我们跟弗来迪一起去过太空夏令营
We're friends from… Space Camp。I went to Space Camp with Freddy.
弗来迪！
Freddy！
- 弗来迪？- 有人来找你
- Freddy？- You got company！
弗来德利克！没听到我说话吗？
Frederick！Didn't you hear me？
整个巴尔地摩都听到了 妈
All Baltimore heard you，Ma.
- 你朋友来了 - 朋友？什么…
- Your friends are here。- Friends？What the？
妈！我还得跟你说几次啊？不许带任何人到这里来！
Come on，Ma！How many times I gotta tell you，don't bring people down here？
我都快认不出来了 这就是年轻又留了胡子的汉·索罗吗？发生什么事了？你瘦了好多！
I can't see too good。Is that a young，bearded Han Solo？You've lost so much weight！
没有 我倒长了30磅 那是谁？
No，I gained 30 pounds。Who is that？
- 噢 那是… - 算了 无所谓
- Oh，that's… - Know what？Doesn't matter.
伙计 你又来这里做什么？就是因为你 我得用五台发电机才能保持在线
Dude，what are you doin' here？Cos of you，I'm rocking five generators to stay online.
加上你现在又被人追杀 所以你的来访对我来说也不是什么好事
And since you're being hunted by assassins，this visit is not a healthy use of my time.
嘿 别碰那个好吗？
And hey，don't touch that，all right？
民用波段电台？对你们来说也太小儿科了吧？
CB radio？A little low-tech for you guys，isn't it？
小儿科？哥们儿 那可是 世界末日来临时的保障 明白吗？
That，my friend，is an end-of-the-world insurance system，OK？
就算是最后一块芯片都挂掉了 我还能继续和外界保持联络
So when the last microchip goes down，I can contact whoever's there，
不管对方是具僵尸还是别的什么东西
whether they be zombies or not.
- 你带你爸爸来这里干嘛？- 他很前卫哦 对电玩文化很感兴趣
- What'd you bring your dad here for？- He's cool。He's into the gaming culture.
海报不错
Nice poster.
- 怎么？你很喜欢费特？- 不 我还是比较喜欢星际大战
- Oh，what？Like，you a big fan of the Fett？- No。I was always more of a Star Wars guy.
- 喜欢星际大战…他到底是谁？- 他在开玩笑…他是我的…
- Star Wars guy。Who is this man？- He's my…
嘿！你个笨小子！我不是他爸爸
Hey，dump truck。I'm not his dad.
- 我是个警察 怎么样吧？- 噢 警察 真不好意思 谢谢你了
- I'm a cop。How 'bout that？- Oh。A cop。I'm sorry。Thank you.
你干嘛带个警察来我的控制中心？
Why'd you bring a cop into my command centre？
哈哈哈 控制中心？这不过是个地下室！
Command centre！It's a basement.
- 这是控制中心！- 别说了 麦克连 我可以解释
- It's a command centre！- I can explain.
你告诉我们汤玛斯·盖布尔的事就行了 我们就是为这事儿来的
Just tell us about Thomas Gabriel，all right？That's why we came here.
汤玛斯·盖布尔？哦 很好 我不知道 很抱歉
Thomas Gabriel。I didn't know。Sorry.
出去！我要你们现在给我出去！快！
Get out！I want you outta here，right now.
嘿 冷静点 冷静点！胖小子
Hey，calm down。Just calm down，big boy！
你才冷静点！这是我家！
You calm down！It's my house！
你得告诉我我想知道的 不然我就在你家揍死你
You're gonna tell me what I wanna know，or I'll beat you to death in your own house.
四年前国防部雇用了汤玛斯·盖布尔 做他们的电脑顾问
Four years ago，the DOD recruits Thomas Gabriel to be a cyberspook for 'em，OK？
上任的第一天 他就跟上司说
First day on the job，tells his bosses
这个国家的安全系统 充斥着漏洞 门户洞开
this nation's security infrastructure is open to compromise.
他们说“我们会考虑你的建议的” 但他是个很有责任感的人 并没有就此作罢
They say，「We'll take it under advisement.」 But he don't ease up cos he is committed.
所以他就直接闯进参谋长联席会议
So he breaks into a meeting of the Joint Chiefs of Staff，
仅凭着一台笔记本电脑 就黑掉了 北美空军防卫司令部 关闭了整个国防网络系统
and，with just a laptop，hacks into NORAD and shuts down our defence network.
结果他们就拿枪对着他的脑袋 叫他停止这种攻击行为
So they put a gun to the man's head and forced him to stop the hack.
汤玛斯·盖布尔就是为了证明自己的观点 能用一台笔记本电脑关闭整个北美空防司令部的人
Thomas Gabriel's the guy who shut down NORAD with a laptop just to prove a point.
- 你以为我还会怕你吗？- 告诉我们怎么找到他
- You think I'm scared of you？- Tell us how to find him.
我怎么知道？他是个幽灵 已经从人间消失了
How do I know？He's a ghost，man。He just fell off the grid.
- 这条路也走不通 咱们走吧 - 等等 麦克连
- Another dead end。Come on。- Wait.
“法师” 你听着 几个星期前 我写了…
Listen，Warlock，a couple of weeks ago I wrote a…
我知道 你写了个新加密算法的代码 现在就可能正被汤玛斯·盖布尔用着呢
A mutating algorithmic security code，that's probably being used by Thomas Gabriel now.
不 我们知道这点 好吧 但你知道他用那个代码做什么吗？
No，we know that。Yes。Can you tell us what he's using it for？
不知道 我一直在尝试着找出答案 在这儿 你们看
I don't know。I've been trying to figure that out。Here，look.
现在这个国家里唯一一个 正在使用那块模板的安全系统
The only security system in the country that I can find
就是社会安全局
currently employing that template is the Social Security Administration.
但还并不是在总局里运行 看 而是在伍德隆的这栋大楼里
But they don't use it in the main facility。Look。They use it in this building，in Woodlawn.
- 哇噢 这到底是怎么？上帝！- 我知道 对吧？
- Whoa。What the hell？God！- I know，right？
- 对什么 你们到底在说些什么？- 用电量高得惊人
- What are you talkin' about？- The power consumption's off the charts.
是非常高非常热 都快着火了
It's hot。It's on fire.
那儿怎么会有这些冷却塔？
Why are there chilling towers？
喂
Hello.
什么是冷却塔？
What's a chilling tower？
你看看我一直就是和这种菜鸟合作
See what I've been dealing with？
大型主机群运行会产生很多热量 所以需要冷却系统
Large server farms generate a lot of heat and need to be cooled.
但为什么是在那儿呢？
But why there？
我跟你说 虽然我不知道那里面是什么 但绝对不是社会安全保障号码
I don't know what's in that building，but it's not Social Security numbers.
我这里出现了警报！有人侵入了伍德隆
I got a red flag over here！Someone's hackin' into Woodlawn.
现在正挂载在主机上
Honing in on the host server right now.
“弗来德利克·卡鲁迪斯”
「Frederick Kaludis.」
- 咱们来看看他 - 这头肥猪
- Let's have a look at him。- Fat bastard.
麦克连
McClane.
- 他的女儿现在在哪儿？- 我们追踪到了她的手机讯号
- Where is his daughter？- We just got a trace on her cell.
你一定会很高兴的
You'll love this.
好 让我们来仔细看看你
All right。Let's get a better look at you.
- 弗来迪？- 什么？
- Freddy？- What？
你钻到我网络里来搞什么鬼 呃？
What the hell are you doing dickin'around inside my network？
麦克连？
McClane？
我还以为我已经杀了你呢
I thought I killed you already.
这话我时常听到
I get that sometimes.
- 你能不能追踪到他在哪里？- 可以 伙计
- You think you can try to track where he is？- Dude，yeah.
探长 用手遮住摄影机可并不能关掉麦克风哈
Detective，covering the camera with your hand does not turn off the microphone.
是 我知道在电脑方面我不如你们聪明
Yeah，I know I'm not as smart as you guys with all this computer shit，
不过 嘿 我还活着 不是吗？
but，hey，I'm still alive，ain't I？
而你那边的坏人一定是快死光了吧？呃？
I mean，you got to be runnin' out of bad guys by now，right？Huh？
盖布尔？
Gabriel？
说句实话 你可以告诉我 你是怎么做的？
Honestly，you can tell me。How does that work？
是不是有一种服务？什么800号码之类的？比如说1-800-找帮凶？
You got some kind of service？Some kinda 800 number？1-800-HENCHMEN？
而且我敢打赌你一定还在线上
And I bet you're still on hold with，
喊着“能不能再帮我找一个 死亚洲婊子过来？”是吧？
「Can I get another dead Asian hooker bitch over here right away？」 Huh？
不过说真的 估且不论她的腿功 那个精瘦的女忍者还真是够辣的
But seriously，all that kicking aside，that skinny little ninja chick，she was smokin' hot.
想找这么一个 一定很不容易吧？
One of those gotta be real hard to come by，right？
- 你好像很得意啊？- 我也有值得骄傲的时候
- You're impressed with yourself，aren't you？- I have my moments.
是吗？
Yeah？
那这也是其中之一吗？
Is this one of them？
- 喂？- 这是紧急服务中心
- Hello？- Yes，this is Emergency Services.
- 谢天谢地 - 她听得到我吗？
- Thank God。- Can she hear me？
我叫露西·杰尼洛 我被困在这里好几个小时了 手机也不通
My name is Lucy Gennero。I'm stuck in here。My cell's not working.
她听得到吗？露西 快挂掉电话！
Can she hear this？Lucy，hang up that phone！
请保持冷静 小姐 我们知道你的确切位置
Yes，calm down，miss。We know exactly where you are.
一切都会没事的
Everything is gonna be all right.
- 露西 快挂掉电话！- 拜托 约翰 我正在讲话
- Lucy，hang up the phone！- John，I'm trying to have a conversation.
今晚任务很多 我们有点人手不足 这点我想你也知道
We're a bit overloaded tonight，as you may imagine，
但我向你保证我们会救你出去的
but I assure you we're gonna get you out of there.
- 即使是我必须亲自前去也没问题 - 谢谢你
- Even if I have to come down there myself。- Thank you.
在这期间 你需要我们帮你联系什么人吗？
In the meantime，is there anyone we can contact for you？
是的
Yeah.
我爸爸
My dad.
他叫做约翰·麦克连 是纽约市警察
His name is John McClane。He's a New York City cop.
我们会找到他的 再坚持一下 小姐 我们马上会去救你的
We'll find him。Just hang in there，miss，and we'll get to you… very soon.
谢谢你
Thank you.
哇噢 你女儿真不赖 都等不及要见到她了
Wow。That's a great girl you got there。Can't wait to meet her.
你怎么啦？说不出话来了？
What's the matter？Cat got your tongue？
来呀 约翰
Come on，John.
讲个笑话
Make a joke.
说点儿好笑的
Say somethin'funny.
（乌德隆）
哪儿？你要去哪里？
Where？Where you goin'？
嘿 麦克连 等等 你要去哪里？要干什么？
Hey！McClane！Hold on。Where you goin'？What are you gonna do？
你以为我要去干什么？我要去杀了这个人 救我女儿
What do you think I'm gonna do？I'm gonna go kill this guy and get my daughter.
- 但她可能会在任何地方… - 嘿 听好 接下来会很混乱的 你就留在这儿
- But she can be anywhere… - Listen。It's gonna get messy。Stay here.
- 我想我… - 嘿 我这是在帮你的忙
- I think I… - Hey，I'm doing you a favour.
我自己都没把握 懂了吗？
I wouldn't bet on me，all right？
接下来就由我来吧
I'll take it from here.
谢谢你帮我忙
Thanks for your help.
我对你也没把握 所以我还是该帮你一把
I wouldn't bet on you either，so I figured I'd lend a hand.
系好安全带
Buckle up.
女士 我们是泽西分部的FBI
FBI，ma'am。Jersey field office.
可以看一下你的证件吗？
Mind if I see your ID？
没问题
Not at all.
我爸爸是警察 所以才会有这种习惯
My dad's a cop。Force of habit.
听起来你爸爸倒是个聪明人
Your father sounds like a very smart man.
孩子 你能联络到伯曼吗？
Kid，can you get Bowman？
嗯 可以
Uh，yeah.
完全不通
It's completely dead.
盖布尔一定是关闭了所有卫星通讯 妈的
Gabriel must have shut down all the satellite links。Shit.
关于露西的事 我很抱歉
I'm sorry about Lucy，man.
还有所有这一切
About all of it.
都是我的错 把你牵涉其中 这些其实都不关你的事的
It was my fault you got into this。This wasn't your fight.
没什么好抱歉的
You got nothin' to be sorry about.
- 放开我 你个杂种！- 这贱货真难缠
- Let go of me，you bastard！- This bitch is a handful.
你现在没事了吧？
Are you gonna be all right？
老实点 不然我会伤到你的！
Hey！Behave or I will hurt you.
是吗？那我们两个出去单挑 看是谁能伤到谁
Oh，yeah？Let's step outside，just you and me。We'll see who hurts who.
真是有其父 必有其女
You really are his daughter.
把她的手绑起来
Tie her wrists.
特雷 盖布尔想见你
Trey，Gabriel wants to see you.
- 是时候了吗？- 对
- Is it that time already？- Yeah.
好
OK.
我很快就回来
I'll be back in a second.
别 别 求求你 不要！
No，no，no，please！
有人从外围的通风口侵入
We're showing a breach on an exterior vent.
去看看
Go take a look.
别太久 我们马上要收拾东西走人了
Don't be long。We're packing up soon.
嘿 麦克连 我们是不是该有个计划什么的？
Hey，McClane，do we have anything resembling a plan？
找到露西 杀死其它所有人
Find Lucy and kill everybody else.
不 我是说比这更像是个计划的 比如说 怎么实现你刚说的目标
No，I mean more like a plan。Like，a way to do that.
快
Come on.
好 根据设计图 冷却塔是在最底层
OK，according to the layout，the chilling towers are kept on the bottom level.
还好没上锁
I think mine's locked.
好 看来我们的确是到了关键地带了
OK。Now it looks like we're gettin' somewhere.
呃…
Uh…
看起来控制冷却系统的主机应该是在…
OK，this looks like it controls the cooling system for the mainframe，which should be…
如果我能侵入到这里…
If I can just hack in…
触动警铃 这样可能就会引起伯曼的注意
and trip the alarm，it might alert Bowman.
有人触动了警铃
Someone set off the alarms.
谢谢你了 警探 我也能听得到 快想法儿关掉它
Yes。Thank you，detective。I can hear that。Find a way to turn it off.
怎么了？
What have you got？
出了问题 乌德隆的警铃响了
We got a problem。The alarms went off at Woodlawn.
一定是他
It's gotta be him.
那乌德隆又是什么？
And what's Woodlawn？
是国家安全局 它是设在巴尔地摩城外的一个安全设施点
It's NSA…a secure facility outside of Baltimore.
在我们9/11之后建的一项安全设施 为的是在危机时备份所有的金融资料
It's a fail-safe we built after 9/11 to back up all financial information.
一旦网络遭到入侵 所有的金融资料就会 自动被下载到那边的主机做为备份
The moment networks were hit，all financial data began downloading to those servers.
银行、华尔街、企业档案、政府基金… 所有这些
Banks，Wall Street，corporate records，government funds，all of it.
基本上就是整个美国所积累的财富总和
Basically，a backup for the accumulated wealth of America.
全都在一个地点？
All in one location？
盖布尔又能用它来做什么呢？
What could Gabriel do with it？
如果他能进得去 就可以把资料都转到移动硬盘上
If he could get in，he might try to transfer the data to a portable hard drive.
然后他就可以在任何地方操控这些帐户 把几十亿元收归囊中
Then he'd have access to those accounts from anywhere。Siphon off billions for himself.
而我们完全无法追踪到
We couldn't trace it.
或者 以我对他的了解 他可能会删除所有资料 让我们一文不名 回到石器时代
Or，knowing him，he could erase it all and send us all back to the Stone Age.
- 为什么你们没告诉过我这件事？- 说实话 以你的职位级别还不够格
- Why the hell wasn't I told about this？- Frankly，it's above your pay grade.
我不够格？
My pay grade？
如果连我都不知道 那盖布尔到底是怎么知道的？
How the hell did Gabriel find out about this when even I didn't know about it？
他就是设计者
He designed it.
这是他设计的程序
It was his program.
他知道昨晚黑掉你的系统后 下载就会自动开始
He knew that hacking your system last night would trigger the download.
真聪明！
That's brilliant.
你们这两个天才 别在这儿挡我的道了
You two geniuses，stay out of my way.
让我看看能不能找到这地方的地面分布图
Let me see if I can get a floor plan of this place.
不许动！
Don't move！
你！离开电脑！快点！
You，get away from the bag。Now！
好 好
OK，OK.
我们一直在等你
We've been waiting for you.
是吗？我也一直在等你
Yeah？I've been waiting for you，too.
麦克连！
McClane！
孩子？
Kid？
马特？
Matt？
孩子！
Kid！
艾默森
Emerson.
有一个冷却塔好像出了点问题
We have a problem in one of the cooling towers.
- 七号塔 - 七号塔
- Tower seven。- Tower seven.
去看看出了什么事
Find out what's going on.
好 我去看看
Arrivo subito。OK.
长官？
Sir？
让你的队伍准备待命 我们得去乌德隆
Get the HR team to stand by。We need to get to Woodlawn.
路全都堵死了 现在华盛顿地区被挤得水泄不通
The roads out are blocked。DC's in total gridlock.
那就去弄几架直升机
Then get us some helicopters.
直升机都被五角大楼调去做搜救工作了
They were all pulled by the Pentagon for search and rescue.
莫利纳 马上去给我弄几架他妈的直升机
Molina，find me some goddamn helicopters immediately.
听着 五角大楼正在让战斗机 在华盛顿上空巡查
Look，the Pentagon has jets flying CAP over DC.
让他们派一架到乌德隆 在我们到达前要密切监视一切动向
Have them send one to Woodlawn and keep an eye on things.
咱们出发
Let's go.
我女儿她在哪儿？
Where's my daughter？
鲁索 回话
Russo，check in.
我想鲁索现在正往黄泉路上 去见你女友呢 混帐
Yeah，I think Russo's on his way down to meet your girlfriend，dickhead.
等一下 他好像还有话说
Hold on a minute。Looks like he's coming around.
是麦克连！他在3楼！
It's McClane！He's on the third floor！
都听到了？没错
Get all that？That's right.
我就在3楼 不过我马上要去找你了
I'm on the third floor。But I'm coming to get you.
别动 我会找医生来的
Don't move now。I'll send a doctor.
杀了这家伙 我把麻衣的那份分给你
Kill this guy and I'll give you Mai's cut.
一言为定
Je vous rejoins.
我的加密程序
My algorithm.
好 拜托了
OK，please，God.
拜托拜托 上帝呀…
Oh，please，God…
天！他们是想要钱
Oh，Jesus，they're going after the money.
你要过来找我吗 约翰？那就是你的计划？
You coming to get me，John？Is that the plan？
对 那就是我的计划
Yep，that's my plan.
那你怎么就知道我现在不会 朝你女儿脑袋开一枪呢？
What makes you think I won't put a bullet in your daughter's head？
- 因为你怕我 - 是吗？你以为我怕你？
- Cos you're scared of me。- You think I'm afraid of you？
要不然她早就已经死了 你需要一个谈判筹码
Otherwise she'd be dead already。You need a bargaining chip.
停下！举起手来
Stop there！Hands up.
如果你杀了我 就永远也打不开它了
If you kill me，you'll never get it open.
你小子都做了些什么？
Eccoti qui，piccolo stronzo.
走开 走开！
Move away。Move！
约翰 我认为我们一开始 就对彼此产生了误会
You know，John，I feel like we've gotten off on the wrong foot.
正因为如此 你认为我是个坏人
And because of that，you think I'm the bad guy.
但这是大错特错的 我才是好人
Nothing could be further from the truth。I'm the good guy.
我告诉过他们如果不做好准备 这种事情是会发生的
I told them this could happen if they didn't prepare.
他们有感谢我吗？没有！我反倒被他们毁了 可他们就是不听
Did I get a thank-you？No，I got crucified。But they wouldn't listen.
- 那你现在引起他们的注意力了 不是吗？- 没错
- You got their attention now，don't you？- That's right.
- 我是在帮这个国家的忙 - 哈 帮它弄得四分五裂是吗？
- I am doing the country a favour。- By tearing it apart.
被我破坏总比被外人破坏要好 比被那些相信世界末日的宗教狂热份子破坏要好
Better me than some outsider。Some religious nut-job bent on Armageddon.
没有人想看到那种情况发生的
Nobody wants to see that happen.
所有我破坏的东西都可以被修复 只要国家愿意出钱
Everything I've broken can be fixed if the country is willing to pay for it.
啊 屁话！永远都只是为了钱
Ah，bullshit。It's always been about the money.
怎么？我这么辛苦的工作不该得到酬劳吗？我可是拼了命地在工作啊 约翰
What？I shouldn't get paid for my work？I'm working my ass off here，John.
那就坐好了等着吧 混账东西 我有张支票要给你呢
Well，just sit tight，asshole。I got a cheque for you.
我没办法和他说话 你跟他说吧 看能不能让他听进去
I can't talk to this guy。You talk to him，see if you can get him to focus.
爸？
Dad？
嗨 宝贝
Hi，baby.
现在他们只剩下五个人了
Now there are only five of them.
坚持住 露西 我来了
Hang on，Lucy。I'm comin'.
谁能不能给我杀了这狗娘养的！
Would somebody please kill this son of a bitch？
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem.
其实也没有什么麻烦 我只是下错了楼层
There's actually no problem。I just got off on the wrong floor.
全乱套了
This is a mess.
哇 我真佩服你 要破解整个国家的所有财政资料
Wow。I'm truly impressed，man。Hacking every byte of financial data
得需要几个星期的时间 除非你能先消除网络拥挤状况
for the entire country'd take weeks unless you eliminated the congestion.
这次末世入侵就是为了这个吧？
That's what this fire sale is about，isn't it？
- 真是太高明了！- 对 是很高明 请你安静点
- That's brilliant。- Yes，it is。Please be quiet.
- 混蛋 - 你是谁？
- Asshole。- Who are you？
马特·法瑞尔
Matt Farrell.
露西·麦克连
Lucy McClane.
我还以为你姓杰尼洛 露西·杰尼洛
I thought your name was Gennero。Lucy Gennero.
今天不是
Not today.
- 你能破解密码吗？- 也许吧 如果我有足够时间的话
- Can you crack the code？- Maybe。I mean，if I had enough time.
这可真令人鼓舞啊
That's encouraging.
带上他们走
Take them with us.
- 咱们走 - 咱们走
- Let's go。- Let's go.
盖布尔 国防部刚派了架F-35 朝我们这边过来了
Gabriel，Pentagon just sent an F-35 towards us.
监视着它
Keep an eye on it.
开始破解攻击指令密码
Pulling down the 「go」 codes now.
你也许该开始想想 墓碑上要写点儿什么了 混蛋
You might wanna think about what you want on your headstone，asshole.
靠 他妈的跟老鼠一样！
Christ。Goddamn hamster！
来吧
There you go.
别动啊 蜘蛛小子！
Stay still，spider-boy！
这就对了
That's right.
该死！
Goddammit！
哦 不要啊！
Oh，no！
说真的 你不应该激怒他们 他们可都是荷枪实弹哪
You probably shouldn't antagonise them，since they have all the loaded guns.
深吸一口气 好好找找看你的胆量在哪里 因为你会需要的
Take a minute and dig deep for a bigger set of balls，cos you're gonna need 'em.
哇 这语气好熟悉 只是从一个 有头发的人嘴里说出来感觉好像…怪怪的
Wow。I know that tone。It's just weird hearing it from someone… with hair.
长官
Sir.
预计15分钟到达
ETA 15 minutes.
下来吧
There we go.
弄好它
Fix it.
为什么？我一弄好你就会杀了我 这点我清楚
Why？You're just gonna kill me if I fix it。I know that.
可恶
Oh，shit.
我不会这么做的
I'm not gonna do it.
- 哦 不要不要 可恶！- 罗宾森好像开得太快了
- Oh，no，no，no！Shit！- Robinson is coming pretty fast.
- 什么 你说什么？- 有点不对劲
- I'm sorry，what？- Something's wrong.
罗宾森开得太快了
Robinson is coming too fast.
那不是罗宾森
It's not Robinson.
那一定是我爸爸
That would be my dad.
弗来迪？
Freddy？
是我 约翰·麦克连
It's John McClane.
我知道你能听到 这是你的频率 对吧？666
Look，I know you can hear me。This is your frequency，right？666.
快点 拿起麦克风 弗来迪
Come on，pick up the mic，Freddy.
这里没有你要找的人 对不起
Nobody here by that name。Sorry.
混蛋黑客！
Hackerjerk-off！
“法师”
Warlock…
我想要你尽一切可能帮我联络上FBI
I need you to do whatever it is you do to patch me through to the FBI.
帮我联络上副局长伯曼
To Deputy Director Bowman.
- 你听到了吗？- 你是认真的？
- You hear me？- Are you serious？
你要我这样用黑的方法给你去接通
You want me to intentionally open up a com line
FBI网络犯罪小组的头头？开什么玩笑
to the head of the FBI's cyber division？I don't think so.
弗来迪 该死 他们抓了我女儿！
Freddy，goddammit，they have my daughter！
我可以帮你 稍等
I can do that。Hold on.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这里是中心 有人要找伯曼主任
This is Central。We have a patch for Director Bowman.
长官 中心找你
Sir。Central's trying to reach you.
请说
Go.
- 伯曼 我是麦克连 - 麦克连
- Bowman，it's McClane。- McClane.
听我说 盖布尔在往北的695公路上 他开的是运危险物质的公用车
Listen to me。Gabriel is on the 695 headed north in a Hazmat truck.
等等 盖布尔已经离开乌德隆了？我们正赶往那里呢
Wait，Gabriel's left Woodlawn？We're headed there right now.
伯曼 他们抓了我女儿
Bowman。He's got my daughter.
听好 这辆运危险物质的车是政府公用的 所以应该有防盗追踪系统 对吗？
Listen，this Hazmat truck is a government vehicle，so it should be LoJacked，right？
追踪到那台车就可以追踪到盖布尔
Track that down，it should take you to him.
- 告诉我车牌号 - 好 等一下 记好了
- Give me the tag number。- All right。Hang on。Here it comes.
G…T…
Golf… Tango…
5…9…2…N
five… niner… two… November.
记下了 麦克连 法瑞尔在哪里？
Got it。McClane，where is Farrell？
跟他们在一起
He's with them.
听我说
Listen to me.
我要进去救露西 可如果我有什么不测的话
I'm gonna go in there and get Lucy out，but if something happens to me，
你必须派援军进去 听到没？派所有人进去
you gotta send the cavalry in，you hear me？I mean everybody.
别让那疯子抓走我女儿 你听到没？
Don't let that maniac get my daughter.
- 约翰 别担心 - 我要你向我保证 伯曼
- John，don't worry。- I want your word，Bowman.
我保证
Yeah，you have it.
麦克连回话完毕
McClane out.
F-35来了
There's the F-35.
你破解攻击指令密码了吗？
Did you get the 「go」 codes？
- 特雷？攻击指令密码破解了吗？- 是 破解了
- Trey。Did you get the 「go」 codes？- Yes.
让我和飞行员说话
Can you connect me to the pilot？
嗯…
Uh…
正在隔离他的无线电讯号
Isolating his radio.
现在向他发送攻击指令
Sending him the 「go」 codes.
AV-81
AV-81.
- AV-81，这里是海军陆战队空翼航空指挥中心 - AV-81听命
- AV-81，this is Marine Air Wing ATC。- Go for AV-81.
已确定你防区内有搭载恐怖分子的车辆行驶 是一台大型货柜车
Confirmed terrorist vehicle located in your sector。A big rig truck.
- 现正在追逐一辆危险物品运输车 - 我看到了 指挥中心
- Currently in pursuit of a Hazmat vehicle。- I see them.
你现在有权对其进行攻击并摧毁它
You are authorised to engage and destroy.
收到 AV-81开始进行攻击
Copy that。AV-81 engaging.
搞什么鬼？
What？
他妈的！
Jesus Christ！Goddammit！
你打错人了！
You're shooting at the wrong guy！
宝贝儿 我想你爸爸大概不会来了
I don't think Daddy's coming，honey.
嘿！蠢货！
Hey！Jackass！
就这两下子而已？呃？
Is that it？Huh？
这就是你的完美一击吗？
Is that your best shot？
挺住！
Come on！
该死！
Damn！
拜托！
Come on！
快走 快！
Let's go。Come on！
这边走 这边 快！
That way。It's that way。Go！
我们三分钟后就离开
We are leaving in three minutes.
你只有一分钟时间
You have one.
规则还是没变啊 我一解开密码你就会杀了我的
The rules haven't changed。You'll kill me the minute I unlock it.
- 哦 他妈的！他妈的！- 马修？
- Oh，shit！Oh，shit！- Matthew？
马修！
Matthew！
我真的需要你专心一些
I really need you to pay attention.
- 规则永远都可以改变 - 好 等一下
- The rules can always change。- OK，wait.
- 我在十秒钟内就要对她开枪了 - 等一下
- I'm gonna shoot her in ten seconds。- Wait.
9…
Nine.
我不行
I can't.
8…
Eight.
我怎么能…
I can't.
上帝！
Oh，God.
够了！
OK！
好 好 好！
OK，OK，OK！
6…
Six.
停！停！我做！我做！
OK，stop！Stop，stop！I'm doing it。I'm doing it！
上帝 我的上帝呀
Oh，God。Oh，my God.
联邦探员朝这边过来了
Feds are headed this way.
- 把所有东西都装上飞机 - 是
- Get everything on the plane。- Yep.
- 爸！- 小心
- Dad！- Careful.
别担心 宝贝 一切都会没事的
Don't worry，baby。Everything's gonna be all right.
爸爸！
Daddy！
不！
No！
抓住她
Hold this.
不！
No！
老天
Jesus Christ.
你这回抓住她了？
You got her？
你确定？
You're sure？
不过她倒是勇气可嘉
Nice effort，though.
- 马修！- 哦 该死 好 好！
- Matthew！- Oh，shit！All right，OK！
我做 我做
OK！I'm doin' it。I know.
麦克连
McClane.
你能帮我个忙吗？
Would you do me a favour？
我知道你快不行了 不过你再撑着点
I know the lights are beginning to dim，but if you could just hang on for a second，
等马特做完了 我就杀了他 再杀了你女儿
when Matt's finished，I'm gonna kill him and your daughter，
而我真得很希望你能看到这一幕
and I would love for you to see that.
他妈的 马修？
Goddammit。Matthew？
再给十秒行吗？再过十秒你就能有所有的钱了
Ten seconds，OK？You'll have all your money.
- 你可以离开 没人必须要受伤 好吗？- 再过几秒 你给我待好
- You just leave。No one has to get hurt，OK？- A few seconds。Stay with me.
麦克连！
McClane！
你给我待好
Stay with me.
爸？
Dad？
你的墓碑上应该这么写 “总是在错误的时间出现在错误的地方”
On your tombstone it should read，「Always in the wrong place at the wrong time.」
不如写“爽死啦！操你…”
How about，「Yippee-ki-yay，motherf…」
爸…爸…
Daddy… Daddy… Daddy…
- 你还好吗？- 是的 宝贝儿 我挺好的
- Are you OK？- Yes，baby，I'm fine.
我知道你会来救我
I knew you'd come for me.
我当然会来救你的 宝贝 抱歉我用了这么久才救你出来 我没事的
Of course I'd come for you，honey。Sorry it took me so long。It's OK.
快 快
Move，move.
不许动！
Freeze！
等等 等等！都是自己人
Hold，hold！He's OK.
- 到车那边去 - 绕过去！绕过去！
- Get that vehicle。- Come around！
- 来 扶爸爸起来 - 好
- Here，help Daddy up。- OK.
哦！等会儿 等会儿 我看我还是先坐在这里休息一下好了
Oooh！Wait，wait。I think I'll just stay here for a minute.
- 好的 爸 你真是疯了 - 怎么了？
- OK。Daddy，you're outta your mind。- What are you talkin' about？
- 你开枪打你自己诶！- 在当时是个不错的想法
- You shot yourself！- It seemed like a good idea at the time.
别告诉这些人我这么做了
Don't tell these guys that I did that.
- 谢谢你帮了我们 约翰 - 别客气
- Thanks for all your help，John。- Thank you.
他还好吗？
Is he OK？
- 我应该把手举起来吗？- 不 不用举手
- Should I put my hands up？- No，don't put your hands up.
那就放下面点儿？
Put 'em down further？
可能会在前往医院的途中休克死亡
Might die of shock on the way to the hospital.
好吧
All right.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
- 嘿 - 哦 嘿！
- Hey。- Oh，hey.
- 中弹的感觉怎么样？- 其实还不错
- How's it feel to be shot？- It actually feels great.
他给我打了一些…叫什么？
He gave me some… What's it called？
- 吗啡 - 吗啡
- Mor？- Morphine.
- 好啊 你现在也有了“功绩勋章”了 - 是么 可我还不知道它能意味着什么
- Well，you got your merit badge now。- Yeah。I don't know what that means.
- 还有就是 女人们喜欢男人的疤痕 - 真的？嗯
- Plus，you know，chicks dig scars。- Really？Hm.
除了那个以外
Not that one.
- 什么？- 你想都别想
- What？- Don't even think about it.
你怎么知道我在想什么？她对你说了什么吗？
How did you know what I was thinking？Did she say something to you？
- 我觉得我们好像有点…来电… - 别想太多 那只是吗啡在作怪
- I felt like we had kind of a vibe。- Easy。That's just the morphine kickin' in.
是么
Yeah.
而且 在我们一起经历这么多事后 我真不想因为这个再痛扁你一顿
Besides，after all we've been through，I'd hate to have to beat you to death.
那样的确不太好
That would suck.
- 可以走了吗？- 是 都准备好了
- Good to go？- Yeah，all set.
好好保重 咱们医院见
Take care of yourself。I'll see you at the hospital.
嘿
Hey.
- 谢谢你救了我女儿的命 - 嗯…
- Thanks for saving my daughter's life。- Hey…
我还能怎么做呢？
What was I gonna do？
所以你才能成为英雄
That's what makes you that guy.
对…
Yeah.
那 嗯 他有提到我吗？
So，um，did he say anything about me？
老天哪 露西
Jesus，Lucy.
怎么了？对不起 我只是问问
What？I'm sorry。I'm just asking.
我现在已经够痛苦的了
I'm in enough pain already.
去医院吧
Hospital.